<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://praveenjuge.github.io/feed-reader/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-10-17T18:40:33.871Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.3</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://praveenjuge.github.io/feed-reader/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://praveenjuge.github.io/feed-reader/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[100 Bytes of CSS to look great everywhere]]></title>
        <id>https://swyx.io/css-100-bytes</id>
        <link href="https://swyx.io/css-100-bytes"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T21:05:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Simple grab and go upgrade to the base user agent stylesheet to make for readable sites]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Swyx.io RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My retirement seminar]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/10/my-retirement-seminar/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/10/my-retirement-seminar/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T19:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In precoronatimes I attended an end of year BBQ luncheon put on by my financial advisor at Edward Jones. I’m financially engaged with Kevin and I like Texas BBQ, so I thought I’d go. I also thought my former neighbor Cleo was going to be there and wouldn’t it be fun to surprise her.
Cleo didn’t show up. Foiled! I thought she always went to this thing. Ugh. Okay. Reset. I made due, grabbed a plat of free BBQ and sat down. I was now on my own in a sea of retirees running the same free BBQ grift I was running. There were two people under 60: my financial advisor and the person he invited to be the guest speaker. I failed at making small talk, so my tablemates and I sat the long table poking at our meats and the conversation centered around passing the potato salad.
I wasn’t prepared to hear a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blaming Screen Readers 🚩×5]]></title>
        <id>https://adrianroselli.com/?p=11924</id>
        <link href="https://adrianroselli.com/2021/10/blaming-screen-readers-red-flag.html"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T13:15:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The title of this post is pretty specific. It relates to the meme on Twitter where users identify a trait or preference that they see as problematic, and identify it as a red flag. The emoji represents the red flag. For example: A stylized red flag Blaming Screen Readers 🚩🚩🚩🚩🚩…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrian Roselli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.3]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.3</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.3"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T00:01:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: broken links in documentation
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @hirdot]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UX Designer Salary – How much do UX/UI Designers Make? Entry Level Range]]></title>
        <id>61063abe3306a507d1bfbfb0</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/ux-designer-salary-how-much-do-ux-ui-designers-make-entry-level-range/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T17:39:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you are new to tech, you might have just discovered UI/ UX design and want to pursue that career path. But what is the starting salary for entry level UX/UI designers? In this article, I will provide definitions for UI/ UX design as well as starting salary information]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Delete a Page in Word – Remove Blank or Extra Pages]]></title>
        <id>61694be680d82d07c45a51bf</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-delete-a-page-in-word-remove-blank-or-extra-pages/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T16:49:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're using Microsoft Word, you don't want blank pages appearing in the middle of your document, or extra pages at the end.  These extra pages could be caused by tables, hitting the ENTER key too many times, unnecessary section breaks, unintentional page breaks, extra paragraph markers, and more.  You]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IPV4 vs IPV6 – What is the Difference Between IP Addressing Schemes?]]></title>
        <id>61680b4480d82d07c45a4661</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/ipv4-vs-ipv6-what-is-the-difference-between-ip-addressing-schemes/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T16:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Internet is one of our greatest inventions.  Millions of people use the Internet every second of the day, and it has changed many aspects of our lives – from creating new jobs and a new way of working to influencing how news is consumed and how decisions are made.  Although]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expandable Sections Within a CSS Grid]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353473</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/expandable-sections-within-a-css-grid/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T16:18:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I love CSS Grid. I love how, with just a few lines of code, we can achieve fully responsive grid layouts, often without any media queries at all. I’m quite comfortable wrangling CSS Grid to produce interesting layouts, while keeping …
The post Expandable Sections Within a CSS Grid appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kev Bonett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Cloudflare’s Technology Partner Program]]></title>
        <id>61688bccc2a0ee02a722c828</id>
        <link href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/technology-partner-program/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We aim to continue expanding our ecosystem of programs and partners to make it seamless for our customers to use Cloudflare. To support our growing ecosystem of partners, we are excited to launch our Technology Partner Program.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Lewis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kicking Off Cloudflare's Summer 2022 Internship Program]]></title>
        <id>61688ea9c2a0ee02a722c876</id>
        <link href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/kicking-off-cloudflares-summer-2022-internship-program/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T15:11:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This upcoming summer, we expect to have the largest intern class ever at Cloudflare.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ellie Jamison</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why don’t video games take sex seriously?]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/10/video-game-sex/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/10/video-game-sex/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T14:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week I came across an article titled “Why don’t video games take sex seriously?”… so naturally I clicked it. I was pleased to find the article featured Robert Yang, one of my favorite game designers that I follow on Twitter. I like Yang because our lives are so entirely dissimilar; I’m a straight white guy who makes corporate websites and he’s a gay asian man who makes a lot of homoerotic sex simulator games. If I recall correctly, I started following him about five years ago because of this tweet about level design and I was hooked. Even though I’m not the target audience of his controversial (but yet not controversial) games, I admire and appreciate Yang’s work.
Back to the article about video game sex. One particular passage stuck out to me…
Bodies in games don’t feel soft, Yang po…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boolean shorthands and truthiness]]></title>
        <id>https://gomakethings.com/boolean-shorthands-and-truthiness/</id>
        <link href="https://gomakethings.com/boolean-shorthands-and-truthiness/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today in the current session of Vanilla JS Academy, my students are working on a character and word count script.
My solution for counting words looks like this.
// Split the text content into an array, using spaces to break words // Use Array.filter() to remove any words without a length // (this removes double spaces in the content) let words = text.value.split(' ').filter(function (word) { return word.length; });  One of my students has a solution that looks like this.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Go Make Things</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[💾 Save the date for GitHub Game Off 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=60666</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2021-10-15-save-the-date-for-github-game-off-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T14:28:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Game Off is an annual game jam (or “hackathon for building games”) that’s a little different from most—it lasts for the entire month of November—not just a weekend or a few days. It’s the perfect]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lee Reilly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[W3C TPAC 2021 Exhibition Space opens for registration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9288</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9288"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T13:24:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[W3C’s annual technical meeting, TPAC, has a unique feature this year – an Exhibition Space that is open to the public! If you’re interested in learning about solutions that you can leverage, then register to come visit us. The W3C TPAC Exhibition Hall is open from 18 – 24 October so please stop by and […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Coralie Mercier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“Look, Ma, no probes!” — Characterizing CDNs’ latencies with passive measurement]]></title>
        <id>616978acc2a0ee02a722cb90</id>
        <link href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/cdn-latency-passive-measurement/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T13:02:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A challenge with measuring and comparing network performance is the lack of large-scale global performance metrics, like RTT measurements. In this article we describe an alternative approach to active measurements, which accurately predicts network latencies using only passively collected data.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vasilis Giotsas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multi-User IP Address Detection]]></title>
        <id>616889c7c2a0ee02a722c7e4</id>
        <link href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/multi-user-ip-address-detection/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T13:01:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’ve devised novel methods to detect multi-user IP addresses, and today we’re excited to announce their integration into our global threat intelligence products. These will improve the quality of our detection techniques and reduce false positives for our customers, and the clients that visit them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Chen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Geo Key Manager: Setting up a service for scale]]></title>
        <id>61687f92c2a0ee02a722c789</id>
        <link href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/scaling-geo-key-manager/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T13:00:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Diagnosing scaling issues in a service associated with TLS termination through a deep dive into some of the incidents it caused.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tanya Verma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tips And Tricks For Evaluating UX/UI Designers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/tips-tricks-evaluating-ux-ui-designers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/tips-tricks-evaluating-ux-ui-designers/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Customers may start using your app because you offer a unique product, but user experience is what makes them stay. For that, you need excellent UX designers, and the know-how to spot them when hiring.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nataliya Sambir)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[React.useEffect Hook – Common Problems and How to Fix Them]]></title>
        <id>61686f8b80d82d07c45a4e4a</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/most-common-react-useeffect-problems-and-how-to-fix-them/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T22:07:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[React hooks have been around for a while now. Most developers have gotten pretty comfortable with how they work and their common use cases. But there is one useEffect gotcha that a lot of us keep falling for. The use caseLet's start with a simple scenario. We are building a]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone Downloads Folder – Where are my Downloads? iOS and iPad]]></title>
        <id>615d559e0d91c9077974d3ec</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/iphone-downloads-folder-where-are-my-downloads-ios-and-ipad/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T21:59:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone and iPad both have an app called Files where you can locate all of your files from services including iCloud Drive, Dropbox, and more.  If you want to access the Downloads folder, you can find it inside the Files app. In this article, I will show you how to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Get into BIOS in Windows 10 – BIOS Setup PC Guide]]></title>
        <id>6167f81c80d82d07c45a4630</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-get-into-bios-in-windows-10-bios-setup-pc-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T21:03:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BIOS stands for Basic Input/Output System. It is embedded into computers as a motherboard chip and is primarily responsible for booting the computer system.  Apart from booting up your computer, BIOS is responsible for a lot of other functionality behind the scenes – like managing data flow between an operating]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Make an NFT in 14 Lines of Code]]></title>
        <id>6163d60c804854468fda82ca</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-make-an-nft/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T17:49:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[High-profile celebrities like Jay-Z and Snoop Dog are getting into NFTs. With the cheapest CryptoPunk selling for 103 ETH (~360,000 USD at the time of this article), it is an excellent time for us developers to learn more about the engineering behind them to start building things. At the]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Start an Open Source Project on GitHub – Tips from Building My Trending Repo]]></title>
        <id>615da5e40d91c9077974dd6a</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-start-an-open-source-project-on-github-tips-from-building-my-trending-repo/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T17:09:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Developers around the world use GitHub to share their projects with the global developer community.  In this article, I'll give you some opinionated tips to help you build a great open-source project you can start using. You can also use these tips for building hackathon projects. Quite recently I ended]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 Best Job Boards for Marketers (+ Bonus Suggestions)]]></title>
        <id>https://ahrefs.com/blog/?p=135941</id>
        <link href="https://ahrefs.com/blog/best-job-boards-for-marketers/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T16:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To answer this question, we asked Twitter for some recommendations, added those we’ve personally used into the mix, and spent some time poking around each of them. Here’s what made the cut in our round-up of the best marketing job boards…
Read more ›]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Liew</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Student developer resources you won’t find in the classroom]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=60582</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2021-10-14-student-developer-resources-wont-find-classroom/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T15:53:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Heading back to school? Did you just graduate? The GitHub Education Stream Team (GEST) is sharing resources, tools, and more to help emerging developers land a job. Student leaders from around the world are creating and hosting shows to grow the tech community and share information you won’t find in the classroom.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Juan Pablo Flores Cortés</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rotate Screen in Windows 10 – How to Flip Your Monitor Orientation 90 Degrees]]></title>
        <id>6162db83804854468fda7b4c</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/rotate-screen-in-windows-10-how-to-flip-your-monitor-orientation-90-degrees/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T15:39:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Windows 10 has a built-in feature that lets you flip or rotate your monitor screen just like you can do on your smartphone.  In this article, I will show you how to flip or rotate the monitor of your Windows 10 machine in several orientations such as reverse-landscape, portrait, and]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build Four Node.js and Express.js Projects]]></title>
        <id>61683f7180d82d07c45a4893</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-six-node-js-and-express-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T15:05:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Node.js and Express.js are popular technologies used for JavaScript backend web development. We just released a 10-hour course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will show you how to create four projects using Node and Express. John Smilga developed this course. John is one of the more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Different Degrees of Custom Property Usage]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353057</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/different-degrees-of-custom-property-usage/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T14:35:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One way to work with Custom Properties is to think of them as design tokens. Colors, spacings, fonts, and whatnot. You set them at the root of the page and use them throughout your CSS. Very useful, and the classic …
The post Different Degrees of Custom Property Usage appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Embedded Analytics Made Simple With Cumul.io Integrations]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353243</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/embedded-analytics-made-simple-with-cumul-io-integrations/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T14:32:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[(This is a sponsored post.)
Browse through SaaS communities on Twitter, LinkedIn, Reddit, Discord, you name it and you’ll see a common theme appear in many of them. That theme can go by many names: BI, analytics, insights and …
The post Embedded Analytics Made Simple With Cumul.io Integrations appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cumul.io</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Was it easier to build websites a decade ago?]]></title>
        <id>https://gomakethings.com/was-it-easier-to-build-websites-a-decade-ago/</id>
        <link href="https://gomakethings.com/was-it-easier-to-build-websites-a-decade-ago/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week, Tim McNamara tweeted:
 Why is it harder to make a website in 2021 than it was in 1996?
I mean, writing your own HTML in Notepad and uploading it via FTP was a chore. But it was understandable and easy.
If you want to create a fanpage of some obscure topic, everything is just … too much. So instead, people will create an Instagram/TikTok/Facebook/etc and start posting there.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Go Make Things</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[W3C and Yubico offer first online Web Authentication course for developers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9282</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9282"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T13:13:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[W3C and Yubico announced today the opening of registration for a W3Cx online education course that teaches developers how to build and incorporate modern authentication techniques into their web-based applications using W3C’s Web Authentication (WebAuthn). Both organizations collaborated to design the Massive Open Online Course (MOOC) titled “Introduction to Web Authentication” to equip learners with […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Coralie Mercier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Privacy-Preserving Compromised Credential Checking]]></title>
        <id>6166e7e065133e02a961145d</id>
        <link href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/privacy-preserving-compromised-credential-checking/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T12:59:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing a public demo and open-sourced implementation of a privacy-preserving compromised credential checking service]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Valenta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unbuckling the narrow waist of IP: Addressing Agility for Names and Web Services]]></title>
        <id>6167095265133e02a96114e9</id>
        <link href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/addressing-agility/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T12:59:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IP addresses associated with names, interfaces, and sockets, can tie these things together in a way that IP was never designed to support. This post describes Cloudflare efforts to decouple of IP addresses from names, the latest in a quest for something we’re calling Addressing Agility.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marwan Fayed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Research Directions in Password Security]]></title>
        <id>6166e36a65133e02a961140f</id>
        <link href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/research-directions-in-password-security/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T12:59:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We've been studying password problems, including malicious logins using compromised credentials. Here's what we learned and here's where we think we can go from here with safer password systems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian McQuoid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smart CSS Solutions For Common UI Challenges]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/modern-css-solutions-for-common-problems/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/modern-css-solutions-for-common-problems/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing CSS has probably never been more fun and exciting than it is today. In this post we’ll take a look at common problems and use cases we all have to face in our work and how to solve them with modern CSS. If you’re interested, we’ve also just recently covered [CSS auditing tools](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/03/css-auditing-tools/), [CSS generators](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/03/css-generators/), [front-end boilerplates](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/) and [VS code extensions](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/) — you might find them useful, too.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Public Working Draft: Accessibility of Remote Meetings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9286</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9286"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T07:46:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Accessible Platform Architectures Working Group has published a First Public Working Draft of Accessibility of Remote Meetings. Remote meeting is an umbrella term used to describe real-time discussions or presentations held between two or more parties online. The issues faced by people with disabilities will vary depending on the implementation of accessibility requirements and […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Art of Deception, Lighthouse Score Edition]]></title>
        <id>https://www.zachleat.com/web/lighthouse-deception/</id>
        <link href="https://www.zachleat.com/web/lighthouse-deception/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few very interesting discussions on Twitter have led me to understand that some folks are talking about Lighthouse scores in a way that is—in my opinion—not as forthright as it could be (intentionally or not). Let’s level set a bit and talk a bit about the different flavors of wiggle room:
Super Fast Hardware #
Here’s a screenshot of a Lighthouse result from this morning, October 14th, 2021, run on an old MacBook Air (2012) using Chrome 86.
Here’s the same result on my MacBook Air (M1, 2020) using Chrome 94:
It’s incredible to me the variability effect that your hardware can have: from a 64 on Performance to a 94—that’s a thirty point swing!
Don’t Do This™ Evil Tip: When running Lighthouse, only use the best, beefiest, latest and greatest, most expensive hardware and network connections.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zach Leatherman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[337: ES Modules on CodePen]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.codepen.io/?p=15961</id>
        <link href="https://blog.codepen.io/2021/10/13/337-es-modules-on-codepen/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T23:22:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ES Modules are a native feature of JavaScript! The import and export keywords are actually a mighty powerful thing for a language to have. You can use them right on CodePen of course. For example, with our URL extensions, you can export stuff from one Pen and import it in another without having to use […]
The post 337: ES Modules on CodePen appeared first on CodePen Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bonsai Browser]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353719</id>
        <link href="https://bonsaibrowser.com/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T22:50:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-browser for research that helps programmers think clearly.
With Bonsai, rather than being like, I’m going to go use my web browser now, you hit Option + Space and it brings up a browser. It’s either full-screen or a …
The post Bonsai Browser appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS is Going Gosh-Darned Hog Wild, I Tell Ya What]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352459</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/css-is-going-gosh-darned-hog-wild-i-tell-ya-what/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T15:36:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As someone just sittin’ back watching CSS evolve, it feels like we’re at one of the hottest moments of innovation in CSS history. It was really something when we got flexbox across all browsers, and not terribly long after, grid. …
The post CSS is Going Gosh-Darned Hog Wild, I Tell Ya What appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Less Absolute Positioning With Modern CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353700</id>
        <link href="https://ishadeed.com/article/less-absolute-positioning-modern-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T14:42:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ahmad Shadeed blogs the sentiment that we might not need to lean on position: absolute as much as we might have in the past. For one thing: stacking elements. For example, if you have a stack of elements that should …
The post Less Absolute Positioning With Modern CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vanilla JS Academy for Teams]]></title>
        <id>https://gomakethings.com/vanilla-js-academy-for-teams/</id>
        <link href="https://gomakethings.com/vanilla-js-academy-for-teams/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two years ago, I launched a project-based online JavaScript workshop call the Vanilla JS Academy.
I’d heard from so many people who understood the basics of JS, but struggled to put this pieces together to build actual projects. The program was specifically designed to help students get better at that, and learn how to use JavaScript to solve problems.
It quickly became my most popular product.
Over 600 people have attended the Vanilla JS Academy in the last two years.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Go Make Things</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloudflare and the IETF]]></title>
        <id>6166a9d065133e02a961134c</id>
        <link href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/cloudflare-and-the-ietf/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T12:59:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cloudflare helps build a better Internet through collaboration on open and interoperable standards. This post will describe how Cloudflare contributes to the standardization process to enable incremental innovation and drive long-term architectural change.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Hoyland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pairings in CIRCL]]></title>
        <id>61607c79966cdd02a833baaf</id>
        <link href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/circl-pairings-update/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T12:59:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our Go cryptographic library CIRCL announces support for pairing-based cryptography.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Armando Faz-Hernández</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exported Authenticators: The long road to RFC]]></title>
        <id>6166aa0165133e02a9611351</id>
        <link href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/exported-authenticators-the-long-road-to-rfc/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T12:59:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn more about Exported Authenticators, a new extension to TLS, currently going through the IETF standardisation process.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Hoyland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coalescing Connections to Improve Network Privacy and Performance]]></title>
        <id>61655d7b65133e02a9611159</id>
        <link href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/connection-coalescing-experiments/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T12:59:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Real world experiments for evaluating connection coalescing effects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Talha Paracha</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated Candidate Recommendation: Media Capture and Streams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9280</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9280"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T11:37:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The WebRTC Working Group invites implementation of an updated Candidate Recommendation Snapshot of Media Capture and Streams. This document defines a set of JavaScript APIs that allow local media, including audio and video, to be requested from a platform. Comments are welcome via the GitHub issues by 13 November 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upcoming Live Workshops On Front-End & UX (Oct 2021&ndash;Jan 2022)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/new-smashing-online-workshops-oct-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/new-smashing-online-workshops-oct-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you like a good interface design challenge? What about accessibility testing and design systems? Or maybe Next.js and advanced CSS? With our new online workshops on front-end & design, we cover all of it. Ah, and [here's what our workshops are like](https://vimeo.com/616485526).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Design principles on the Clearleft podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://adactio.com/journal/18527</id>
        <link href="https://adactio.com/journal/18527"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T08:01:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The final episode of season three of the Clearleft podcast is out. Ah, what a bittersweet feeling! On the hand it’s sad that the season has come to an end. But it feels good to look back at six great episodes all gathered together.
Episode six is all about design principles. That’s a topic close to my heart. I collect design principles.
But for this podcast episode the focus is on one specific project. Clearleft worked with Citizens Advice on a recent project that ended up having design principles at the heart of it. It worked as a great focus for the episode, and a way of exploring design principles in general. As Katie put it, this about searching for principles for design principles.
Katie and Maite worked hard on nailing the design principles for the Citizens Advice project. I was able to get some of Maite’s time for her to talk me through it. I’ve also got some thoughts from my fellow Clearlefties Andy and Chris on the topic of design principles in general.
It’s nineteen minutes long and well worth a listen.

And with that, season three of the Clearleft podcast is a wrap!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adactio: Journal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a multi-select component]]></title>
        <id>https://web.dev/building-a-multi-select-component/</id>
        <link href="https://web.dev/building-a-multi-select-component/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post I want to share thinking on a way to build a multi-select component. Try the
demo.
          
  
    Demo
  

If you prefer video, here's a YouTube version of this post:
  
  

Overview #
Users are often presented with items, sometimes lots of items, and in these
cases it can be a good idea to provide a way to reduce the list to prevent
choice overload. This
blog post explores filtering UI as a way to reduce choices. It does this by
presenting item attributes that users can select or deselect, reducing results
and therefore reducing choice overload.
Interactions #
The goal is to enable swift traversal of filter options for all users and their
varying input types. This will be delivered with an adaptable and responsive
pair of components. A traditional sidebar of checkboxes for…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>web.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bootstrap Icons v1.6.0]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.getbootstrap.com/2021/10/13/bootstrap-icons-1-6-0/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.getbootstrap.com/2021/10/13/bootstrap-icons-1-6-0/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bootstrap Icons v1.6.0 adds over 30 new icons, adds official Composer support, includes a new .scss stylesheet for the icon font, plus some other enhancements and bug fixes. Keep reading to see what’s new!
1,400+ icons
We’ve officially passed 1,400 glyphs in Bootstrap Icons with this release—woohoo! Seems utterly insane to me that the project has come this far and there are still so many more icons to include.
We have a few dozen new and updated icons in this release, including:
New brand icons for Apple, Behance, Dribbble, Line, Medium, Microsoft, PayPal, Pinterest, Signal, Snapchat, Spotify, Stack Overflow, Strava, Vimeo, Windows, and WordPress
Two new easel variations
New fingerprint icon
New magic stick
New people variations for rolodex, workspace, and video chat
New webcam icons
New r…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bootstrap Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apply now for GitHub Universe 2021 micro-mentoring]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=60608</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2021-10-12-apply-github-universe-2021-micro-mentoring/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T16:34:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As part of our ongoing commitment to ensure GitHub’s conferences are accessible and inclusive to people from all walks of life, we’re offering 30-minute, 1:1 micro-mentoring sessions with GitHub employees.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Toya East</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Beginner’s Guide to Account-Based Marketing (ABM)]]></title>
        <id>https://ahrefs.com/blog/?p=135888</id>
        <link href="https://ahrefs.com/blog/account-based-marketing/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T16:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This leads to a common paradox—marketing can hit its goals by bringing in a high volume of leads, but sales can’t hit its goals because those same leads are poorly qualified. Account-based marketing (ABM) aims to fix that by tightly…
Read more ›]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mateusz Makosiewicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cop26 Hack Day September 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/info/2021/oct/12/cop26-hack-day-september-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/info/2021/oct/12/cop26-hack-day-september-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T15:45:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In September, in the run up to Cop26, colleagues from across the product and engineering department, as well as other parts of the organisation, came together for another exciting remote hack day focused on the climate crisis
For this virtual hack day of 2021, we had a dedicated focus: Cop26 and the environment. The recent IPCC report makes for grim reading which is why we decided to focus our attention on developing new interactive tools for our readers to stay informed. We produced and presented 19 amazing hacks over the two-day event, including a tool to read product ingredients and determine if they are vegan or not, a visualisation of the world showing data about temperature changes over the last century, an app for extending the life of all your belongings and keeping them out of landfill and an app that uses data from waqi.io to provide the quality of air by location. Below is a selection of the best concepts and designs from the event.
Best conceptual hack: know your rubbish
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rasha Ardati</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What if… you could use Visual Studio Code as the editor of in-browser Developer Tools?]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=6972</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2021/10/12/what-if-you-could-use-visual-studio-code-as-the-editor-of-in-browser-developer-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T15:21:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starting with the next version of Microsoft Edge, we are running an experiment that allows you to use Visual Studio Code as the editor of the in-browser Developer Tools. Here’s a three minute video explaining why we think this is a good idea. Developer Tools have excellent visual tools that allow you to tweak and […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jamstack Developers’ Favorite Frameworks of 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353415</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/jamstack-developers-favorite-frameworks-of-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T14:30:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Which new framework should I learn this year? Is it time to ditch my CMS? What tools should I pick up if I want to scale my site to an audience of millions? The 2021 Jamstack Community Survey is here …
The post Jamstack Developers’ Favorite Frameworks of 2021 appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laurie Voss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Function expressions vs. function declarations revisisted]]></title>
        <id>https://gomakethings.com/function-expressions-vs.-function-declarations-revisisted/</id>
        <link href="https://gomakethings.com/function-expressions-vs.-function-declarations-revisisted/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Four years ago, I wrote the difference between function expressions and function declarations. Since writing that article, I’ve both changed my approach to writing functions and expanded my explanation to capture the nuance of hoisting in JavaScript.
Today, I wanted to share my updated thoughts on writing functions. Lets dig in!
What’s the difference between function expressions and function declarations? There have historically been two ways to write a function.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Go Make Things</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WooCommerce + Google Analytics]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353317</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/woocommerce-google-analytics/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T14:28:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google Analytics is powerful analytics software. A common way to use it is to just slap the JavaScript snippet on every page template you have and let it collect basic data about unique visitors and pageviews and such. That’s  useful, …
The post WooCommerce + Google Analytics appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing SSL/TLS Recommender]]></title>
        <id>6164533765133e02a9610f1c</id>
        <link href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/ssl-tls-recommender/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T13:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing customized recommendations to improve the security of your website.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Suleman Ahmad</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic Process Isolation: Research by Cloudflare and TU Graz]]></title>
        <id>61646f7065133e02a961101c</id>
        <link href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/spectre-research-with-tu-graz/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T12:59:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cloudflare worked with TU Graz to study the impact of Spectre on Cloudflare Workers and to develop new defenses against it. Today we're publishing a paper about our research.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kenton Varda</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Handshake Encryption: Endgame (an ECH update)]]></title>
        <id>61646b3c65133e02a9610fce</id>
        <link href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/handshake-encryption-endgame-an-ech-update/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T12:59:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post, we’ll dig into ECH details and describe what this protocol does to move the needle to help build a better Internet.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher Wood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful React APIs For Building Flexible Components With TypeScript]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/react-apis-building-flexible-components-typescript/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/react-apis-building-flexible-components-typescript/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[React with JSX is a fantastic tool for making easy-to-use components. Typescript components make it an absolute pleasure for developers to integrate your components into their apps and explore your APIs. Learn about three lesser-known React APIs that can take your components to the next level, and help you build even better React Components in this article.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Gaurav Khanna)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bridging The Gap Between Designers And Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/bridging-gap-between-designers-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/bridging-gap-between-designers-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UXPin has recently launched a new feature called “Merge”. This tool aims to break through the chasms of design and development, all while improving the agility and quality our teams expect. This new technology may cause some rethink on how the whole design team and engineering team collaborates.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Matthew Talebi)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Save the date! Get Online Week returns for 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://accessibility.blog.gov.uk/2021/10/12/save-the-date-get-online-week-returns-for-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://accessibility.blog.gov.uk/2021/10/12/save-the-date-get-online-week-returns-for-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T09:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Save the date - it's time to talk about Digital Inclusion.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Accessibility in government</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Public Working Draft: Natural Language Interface Accessibility User Requirements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9275</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9275"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T08:36:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Accessible Platform Architectures Working Group has published a First Public Working Draft of Natural Language Interface Accessibility User Requirements. This document outlines various accessibility-related user needs, requirements and scenarios for natural language interfaces. These user needs should influence accessibility requirements in various related specifications, as well as the design of applications that include natural […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[W3C Invites Implementations of CSS Multi-column Layout Module Level 1]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9277</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9277"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T08:34:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CSS Working Group has published the CSS Multi-column Layout Module Level 1 as a W3C Candidate Recommendation Snapshot. This specification describes multi-column layouts in CSS, a style sheet language for the web. Using functionality described in the specification, content can be flowed into multiple columns with a gap and a rule between them. The […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Who Pays for Web Frameworks?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.zachleat.com/web/monetization/</id>
        <link href="https://www.zachleat.com/web/monetization/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three years into working on Eleventy, I continue to be blown away by the adoption and community support of folks contributing to the underdog.
It has me thinking about sustainability models for this style of web framework—what are other folks doing to fund development? Recent news would suggest that more and more folks are going the route of taking investment. It has me considering the hidden costs of such routes.
Nonetheless, I thought the best place to start would be to compile the data.
Name
      Investment
      Ownership
      💵
    
Angular
      
      Google
      -
    
Astro
      (as Skypack CDN)
      
      Open Collective
    
Eleventy
      -
      -
      Open Collective
    
Gatsby
      $46.8M
      Gatsby (Inc.)
      -
    
Jekyll
      
      originally GitHub
      …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zach Leatherman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Those “Get The App” Banners]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352907</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/those-get-the-app-banners/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T22:12:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why would a company promote a native app over their perfectly usable website?
We’d have to ask them, I suppose. But it’s hard not to see this push to native as a matter of priorities: that these companies consider native 
…
The post Those “Get The App” Banners appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I learned to stop worrying and love TailwindCSS]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28833449</id>
        <link href="https://blog.ohmysmtp.com/blog/why-i-use-tailwindcss/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T21:42:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://blog.ohmysmtp.com/blog/why-i-use-tailwindcss/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28833449
Points: 8
# Comments: 2]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>albertgoeswoof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cash (Tiny jQuery Alternative)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353431</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/cash-tiny-jquery-alternative/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T20:28:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The README for Cash is straightforward:
Cash is an absurdly small jQuery alternative for modern browsers (IE11+) that provides jQuery-style syntax for manipulating the DOM. Utilizing modern browser features to minimize the codebase, developers can use the familiar chainable methods 
…
The post Cash (Tiny jQuery Alternative) appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Show HN: Gust – Tailwind CSS for WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28832456</id>
        <link href="https://www.getgust.com/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T20:09:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.getgust.com/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28832456
Points: 1
# Comments: 0]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>mdsas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub security update: revoking weakly-generated SSH keys]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=60642</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2021-10-11-github-security-update-revoking-weakly-generated-ssh-keys/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T17:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On September 28, 2021, we received notice from the developer Axosoft regarding a vulnerability in a dependency of their popular git GUI client - GitKraken. An underlying issue with a dependency, called `keypair`, resulted in the GitKraken client generating weak SSH keys.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Hanley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transitional apps]]></title>
        <id>https://gomakethings.com/transitional-apps/</id>
        <link href="https://gomakethings.com/transitional-apps/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rich Harris, the guy who created Svelte (learn more about compilers here), gave a talk at Jamstack Conf last week, and its one of the best talks I’ve ever seen.
Rich dug into the issues with both single-page apps and multi-page apps (or, more accurately, websites), and coined a term for a new “somewhere in the middle” approach: transitional apps.
You can watch the whole thing on YouTube now. It’s well worth 20 minutes of your time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Go Make Things</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Better Collaboration With Pull Requests]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352569</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/better-collaboration-with-pull-requests/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T14:29:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article is part of our “Advanced Git” series. Be sure to follow us on Twitter or sign up for our newsletter to hear about the next articles!
In this third installment of our “Advanced Git” series, we’ll look at …
The post Better Collaboration With Pull Requests appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tobias Günther</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[484: Cloudflare, Lying to the Browser, Cloudinary Issues, Vue 2 to Vue 3, and Font Icons]]></title>
        <id>https://shoptalkshow.com/?p=5196</id>
        <link href="https://shoptalkshow.com/484/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T13:45:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're talking about Cloudflare product updates, whether you should lie to the browser about image size, Chris is having Cloudinary issues, Dave's answering questions about upgrading from Vue 2 to Vue 3, a question about Font Awesome icons, and what's the deal with Webhint?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ShopTalk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Autofill Dark Pattern]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/autofill-dark-pattern/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/autofill-dark-pattern/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A “dark pattern” is a deceptive UX pattern that tricks users into doing things they may not really want to do. In this article, Alvaro Montoro does a little experiment to find out how much privacy is taken away from users across three different browsers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Alvaro Montoro)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changing Situation]]></title>
        <id>https://adactio.com/journal/18523</id>
        <link href="https://adactio.com/journal/18523"/>
        <updated>2021-10-10T17:17:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Situation persists. But it has changed. There are no longer any official restrictions to speak of here in England. Instead it’s down to everyone to figure out individually what’s right.
Everyone is evaluating the risks, making calculations and coming to different conclusions. It’s only natural that everyone—myself incuded—thinks they’ve found the Goldilocks zone. “That person is being far too blasé! And that person is being far too cautious! But I’m doing exactly the right thing.”
With that in mind, I’m trying not to be judgemental about the decisions other people are making (apart from the decsion not to get vaccinated—I’m judgemental as hell about those selfish assholes). For example, I wear a mask when I’m on public transport. Other people don’t. I try not to judge them (although re…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adactio: Journal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Rails 6 with Tailwind 2 JIT and Esbuild Without Webpacker]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28819023</id>
        <link href="https://digitmagz.com/using-rails-6-with-tailwind-2-jit-and-esbuild-without-webpacker-b0d5cc13469a"/>
        <updated>2021-10-10T15:13:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://digitmagz.com/using-rails-6-with-tailwind-2-jit-and-esbuild-without-webpacker-b0d5cc13469a
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28819023
Points: 2
# Comments: 0]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nauman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mobile UI components made with Tailwind CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28814248</id>
        <link href="https://tailwind-mobile.com/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-09T23:22:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://tailwind-mobile.com/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28814248
Points: 19
# Comments: 3]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>throwaway888abc</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Composable CSS Animation In Vue With AnimXYZ]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/composable-css-animation-vue-animxyz/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/composable-css-animation-vue-animxyz/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most animation libraries like GSAP and Framer Motion are built purely with JavaScript or TypeScript, unlike AnimXYZ, which is labelled “the first composable CSS animation toolkit”, built mainly with SCSS While a simple library, it can be used to achieve a lot of awesome animation on the web in a short amount of time and little code.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ejiro Asiuwhu)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Case for ‘Developer Experience’]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353429</id>
        <link href="https://future.a16z.com/the-case-for-developer-experience/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T20:23:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A good essay from Jean Yang. 
What I mean by developer experience is the sum total of how developers interface with their tools, end-to-end, day-in and day-out. Sure, there’s more focus than ever on how developers use and adopt tools, and 
…
The post The Case for ‘Developer Experience’ appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Radar · September 2021 Edition]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=60622</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2021-10-08-release-radar-aug-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T18:55:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Northern Hemisphere has hit fall, and the southern is starting to warm into summer. September has been a busy time for our community. Maintainers have been getting their repositories ready for Hacktoberfest, joining us]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle Mannering</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jekyll doesn’t do components? Liar!]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353374</id>
        <link href="https://katiekodes.com/jekyll-components-wysiwyg/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T17:14:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I like the pushback from Katie Kodes here. I’ve said in the past that I don’t think server-side languages haven’t quite nailed “building in components” as well as JavaScript has, but hey, this is a good point:
1. Any basic 
…
The post Jekyll doesn’t do components? Liar! appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lots to see in Firefox 93!]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47407</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/10/lots-to-see-in-firefox-93/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T16:45:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 93 comes with lots of lovely updates including AVIF image format support, filling of XFA-based forms in its PDF viewer and protection against insecure downloads by blocking downloads relying on insecure connections.
The post Lots to see in Firefox 93! appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ruth John</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lots to see in Firefox 93!]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47407</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/10/lots-to-see-in-firefox-93/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T16:45:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 93 comes with lots of lovely updates including AVIF image format support, filling of XFA-based forms in its PDF viewer and protection against insecure downloads by blocking downloads relying on insecure connections.
The post Lots to see in Firefox 93! appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ruth John</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a Tennis Trivia App With Next.js and Netlify]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353066</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/building-a-tennis-trivia-app-with-next-js-and-netlify/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T14:30:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we will be learning how to build a tennis trivia app using Next.js and Netlify. This technology stack has become my go-to on many projects. It allows for rapid development and easy deployment.
Without further ado let’s jump in!…
The post Building a Tennis Trivia App With Next.js and Netlify appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brenley Dueck</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comparing Google Analytics and Plausible Numbers]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353062</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/comparing-google-analytics-and-plausible-numbers/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T14:30:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I saw this blog post the other day: 58% of Hacker News, Reddit and tech-savvy audiences block Google Analytics. That’s an enticing title to me. I’ve had Google Analytics on this site literally from the day I launched it. …
The post Comparing Google Analytics and Plausible Numbers appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Service worker strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://gomakethings.com/service-worker-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://gomakethings.com/service-worker-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just launched a brand new pocket guide on Service Workers. Today, I wanted to take a look at the different types of strategies you can use with service workers.
Let’s dig in!
What is a service worker? A service worker is a special type of JavaScript file that acts like middleware for your site.
Any request that comes from the site and any response it gets back first goes through the service worker file.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Go Make Things</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CEO doesn't care about your CSS strategy, as long as you use Tailwind]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28799487</id>
        <link href="https://ideas.krishnan.ca/your-ceo-doesnt-care-about-your-css-strategy-as-long-as-you-use-tailwind"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T14:12:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://ideas.krishnan.ca/your-ceo-doesnt-care-about-your-css-strategy-as-long-as-you-use-tailwind
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28799487
Points: 8
# Comments: 17]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ajaynomics</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Static-First MadLib Generator With Portable Text And Netlify On-Demand Builder Functions]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/static-first-madlib-generator-portable-text-netlify-builder-functions/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/static-first-madlib-generator-portable-text-netlify-builder-functions/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be building an interactive fiction experience in which a user can insert words that match parts of speech given by the content creator. Let’s go!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Bryan Robinson)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The State of Eleventy (2021) in Two Minutes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.zachleat.com/web/state-of-eleventy/</id>
        <link href="https://www.zachleat.com/web/state-of-eleventy/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maybe you watched last year’s Jamsnack video for Jamstack Conf 2020. It’s that time again! I made a short two minute video for Jamstack Conf 2021.


What’s New in 2021? #
Speed and Simplicity. Productive for beginners, trusted by experts.
Two Million Downloads!
10,000 stars on GitHub
Excellent community events from Eleventy Meetup and the 11ties (Jamstack Toronto)
Eleventy Leaderboards
Choose your own Starter Project: we added a new visual view to our starter project list, complete with automatic updating lighthouse scores for each. Filter the list by projects with four hundos. With new direct links to deploy each of these on Netlify, Stackblitz, and Glitch (when available).
Best-in-class Image Plugin supports first-class SVG and AVIF, works with <img>, <picture>, or even in your CSS (e.g. background-image).
Serverless Plugin:

Render dynamic pages with Progressive Enhancement
Use Distributed Persistent Rendering to render and cache the first request
Battle tested on the home page of 11ty.dev and our author pages
Check out this Rainglow color demo
Data can be fetched at run time (e.g. for live CMS previews) or build time (for maximum speed)
Open source API services

Screenshots
IndieWeb Avatars
Sparklines
Folks are building tools on top of Eleventy:

SSR Web Components with LitHTML
Rocket
Slinkity
Partial Hydration with Preact
and a bunch more I’ve missed I’m sure! Feel free to add yours.
We launched our first 1.0 Beta release! #]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zach Leatherman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RenderingNG deep-dive: LayoutNG]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/layoutng/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/layoutng/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post is a part of a series on the Chromium rendering engine. Check out the rest of the series to learn more about RenderingNG, the architecture, key data structures, and VideoNG.
I'm Ian Kilpatrick,
an engineering lead on the Blink layout team, along with Koji Ishii.
Before working on the Blink team,
I was a front-end engineer (before Google had the role of "front-end engineer"),
building features within Google Docs, Drive, and Gmail.
After around five years in that role I took a large gamble switching to the Blink team,
effectively learning C++ on the job,
and attempting to ramp up on the massively complex Blink codebase.
Even today, I only understand a relatively small portion of it.
I'm grateful for the time given to me during this period.
I was comforted by the fact a lot of "reco…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Renault improved its bounce and conversion rates by measuring and optimizing Largest Contentful Paint]]></title>
        <id>https://web.dev/renault/</id>
        <link href="https://web.dev/renault/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Groupe Renault is a French multinational automobile manufacturer with a presence in over 130 countries. For an automotive group such as Renault, performant brand sites driving more user engagement and conversions mean more business. All of its brand sites aim at providing the best user experience at scale while maintaining flexibility of content and features for localized sites. In this context, performance monitoring is a key stake for the customer experience team which is in charge of developing and maintaining the global platform.
Measuring the business impact of Core Web Vitals #
Measurement in Google Analytics #
Working with fifty-five, its global data partner, Renault set up the web-vitals library, which allows sending to Google Analytics all the Web Vitals metrics from real users in…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>web.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 SEO Metrics That Actually Matter (And 4 That Don’t)]]></title>
        <id>https://ahrefs.com/blog/?p=135920</id>
        <link href="https://ahrefs.com/blog/seo-metrics-to-track/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T23:22:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[But how do you know which are which? You’ll find the answers here. We’ll go through the following 10 SEO metrics worth tracking: Organic traffic Keyword rankings Search visibility Traffic value Organic traffic conversions Referring domains Indexed pages Index coverage…
Read more ›]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michal Pecánek</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vibe Check  №9]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/10/vibe-check-9/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/10/vibe-check-9/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T21:13:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Out on the lake on our neighbor's boat.

September was a good month, a month of rebirth. New projects, rebooting stalled projects, pool closing, kids in school; a rhythm. Walks, boats, ebooks, I even bought a new iPad Mini to support my YouTube and RSS habits. Today my daughter turns six and I’m particularly sensitive to the passage of time. Lots of sunshine, lots of roses, but this month did bring with it some bad news.
Some highlights…

The big news is that Shop Talk started a YouTube series. It’s thrice weekly’ish, 10~20 minute videos over on the CSS Tricks YouTube channel. I wrote a bit about it, but Chris and I are having a good time making videos. We’re up to 12 videos so far. That’s a helluva cadence so there’ll be some breaks, but so far feels pretty sustainable.
I attended Nuxt Na…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub’s guide to Hacktoberfest 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=60590</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2021-10-07-githubs-guide-hacktoberfest-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T18:44:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Giving back to open source projects is a great way to practice skills you don’t get to use in your day job. Check out ways to get involved!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kara Sowles</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Advisory Database now powers npm audit]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=60481</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2021-10-07-github-advisory-database-now-powers-npm-audit/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T16:05:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we’re adding a proxy on top of the GitHub Advisory Database that speaks the `npm audit` protocol.  This means that every version of the npm CLI that supports security audits is now talking directly to the GitHub Advisory Database.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Thomson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Implementing form filling and accessibility in the Firefox PDF viewer]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47372</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/10/implementing-form-filling-and-accessibility-in-the-firefox-pdf-viewer/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T15:13:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year, during lockdown, many discovered the importance of PDF forms when having to deal remotely with administrations and large organizations like banks. Firefox supported displaying PDF forms, but it didn’t support filling them: users had to print them, fill them by hand, and scan them back to digital form. We decided it was time to reinvest in the PDF viewer (PDF.js) and support filling PDF forms within Firefox to make our users' lives easier.
The post Implementing form filling and accessibility in the Firefox PDF viewer appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>bdahl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Implementing form filling and accessibility in the Firefox PDF viewer]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47372</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/10/implementing-form-filling-and-accessibility-in-the-firefox-pdf-viewer/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T15:13:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year, during lockdown, many discovered the importance of PDF forms when having to deal remotely with administrations and large organizations like banks. Firefox supported displaying PDF forms, but it didn’t support filling them: users had to print them, fill them by hand, and scan them back to digital form. We decided it was time to reinvest in the PDF viewer (PDF.js) and support filling PDF forms within Firefox to make our users' lives easier.
The post Implementing form filling and accessibility in the Firefox PDF viewer appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>bdahl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to delete an item from an array with vanilla JavaScript]]></title>
        <id>https://gomakethings.com/how-to-delete-an-item-from-an-array-with-vanilla-javascript/</id>
        <link href="https://gomakethings.com/how-to-delete-an-item-from-an-array-with-vanilla-javascript/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s say you have an array of wizards, like this.
let wizards = ['Gandalf', 'Radagast', 'Merlin'];  You want to remove the second item, Radagast, from the array. How would you do it?
Let’s dig in!
Using the Array.splice() method The Array.splice() method accepts three arguments: start, delete, and items.
The first, start, is the index of the item you want to modify in the array. It’s the only required argument.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Go Make Things</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Day in the Life]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/info/2021/oct/07/a-day-in-the-life</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/info/2021/oct/07/a-day-in-the-life"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T09:59:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the latest post in our ‘Day in the Life’ blog series, in which product and engineering’s digital coordinator, Rasha Ardati, interviews a colleague from the department to reflect on their career and experiences at the Guardian.
When Roberto was 10 years old, he went to the library with his dad. There was a little computer in the corner that caught his interest and he left with every book on computing he could find. At home, Roberto took out a pad of paper and started writing his first code. Years later, when Roberto decided he probably couldn’t follow his original dream of being a mathematician, he decided to pursue a career in computing.
What was the path that eventually brought you to the Guardian?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rasha Ardati</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Freebie: COVID-19 Icon Set (56 Icons, AI, EPS, SVG, PNG)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/freebie-coronavirus-icon-set/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/freebie-coronavirus-icon-set/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every once in a while, we publish [freebies](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/category/freebies/) related to different occasions and themes. We hope that with this icon set, every designer will be able to find their own use case and contribute to saving lives. Free for personal and commercial use.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Anton Tyschenko)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Availability Report: September 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=60566</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2021-10-06-github-availability-report-september-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T16:18:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In September, we experienced no incidents resulting in service downtime to our core services.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Scott Sanders</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Availability Report: September 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/2021-10-06-github-availability-report-september-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2021-10-06-github-availability-report-september-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T16:18:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In September, we experienced no incidents resulting in service downtime to our core services.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Engineering – The GitHub Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[336: Cassie Evans]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.codepen.io/?p=15903</id>
        <link href="https://blog.codepen.io/2021/10/06/336-cassie-evans/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T15:01:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cassie Evans is our special guest this week! Cassie is a front-end developer with a special talent and passion for animation and SVG, as evidenced in part by her amazing work on CodePen. She’s recently became part of the team over at Greensock, a very popular JavaScript-powered animation framework. We got to talk specifically about […]
The post 336: Cassie Evans appeared first on CodePen Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Control your data for good with Rally]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47420</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/10/control-your-data-for-good-with-rally/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T14:55:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a world where data and AI are reshaping society, people currently have no tangible way to put their data to work for the causes they believe in. To address this, we built the Rally platform, a first-of-its-kind tool that enables you to contribute your data to specific studies and exercise consent at a granular level. Mozilla Rally puts you in control of your data while building a better Internet and a better society. 
The post Control your data for good with Rally appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melissa Thermidor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Control your data for good with Rally]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47420</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/10/control-your-data-for-good-with-rally/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T14:55:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a world where data and AI are reshaping society, people currently have no tangible way to put their data to work for the causes they believe in. To address this, we built the Rally platform, a first-of-its-kind tool that enables you to contribute your data to specific studies and exercise consent at a granular level. Mozilla Rally puts you in control of your data while building a better Internet and a better society. 
The post Control your data for good with Rally appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melissa Thermidor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To CSS Debugging]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/guide-debugging-css/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/guide-debugging-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging in CSS means figuring out what might be the problem when you have unexpected layout results. We’ll look at a few categories bugs often fit into, see how we can evaluate the situation, and explore techniques that help prevent these bugs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measuring design on the Clearleft podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://adactio.com/journal/18513</id>
        <link href="https://adactio.com/journal/18513"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T08:01:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new episode of the Clearleft podcast just dropped and I have to say, this is one of my favourites so far. It’s all about measuring design.
There was a bit of a theme running through UX Fest earlier this year. On the one hand, there was all the talk of designers learning to speak the language of business (to get that coveted seat at the table), which means talking in numbers. But on the other hand, isn’t there a real danger in reducing user experience to numbers in a spreadsheet?
For this episode I put the narrative together using lots of snippets from different talks, not just from UX Fest but from previous Clearleft events too. I also got some good hot takes from my colleagues Chris, Andy, and Maite. Oh, and it opens with former US Secretary of Defense, Robert McNamara. If you know, you know.
This episode comes in at 22 and a half minutes and I think it’s well worth your time. Have a listen.

This is the penultimate episode of season three. Just one more to go!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adactio: Journal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Very First Eleventy 1.0 Beta Release]]></title>
        <id>https://www.zachleat.com/web/eleventy-one/</id>
        <link href="https://www.zachleat.com/web/eleventy-one/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[View this blog post on the Eleventy Blog: The Very First Eleventy 1.0 Beta Release]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zach Leatherman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Safe DOM manipulation with the Sanitizer API]]></title>
        <id>https://web.dev/sanitizer/</id>
        <link href="https://web.dev/sanitizer/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Applications deal with untrusted strings all the time, but safely rendering that content as part of an HTML document can be tricky. Without sufficient care, it's easy to accidentally create opportunities for cross-site scripting (XSS) that malicious attackers may exploit.
To mitigate that risk, the new Sanitizer API proposal aims to build a robust processor for arbitrary strings to be safely inserted into a page. This article introduces the API, and explains its usage.
// Expanded Safely !!
$div.setHTML(`<em>hello world</em><img src="" onerror=alert(0)>`, new Sanitizer())
Escaping user input #
When inserting user input, query strings, cookie contents, and so on, into the DOM, the strings must be escaped properly. Particular attention should be paid to DOM manipulation via .innerHTML, where…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>web.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tab Unloading in Firefox 93]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47413</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/10/tab-unloading-in-firefox-93/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T16:52:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starting with Firefox 93, Firefox will monitor available system memory and, should it ever become so critically low that a crash is imminent, Firefox will respond by unloading memory-heavy but not actively used tabs. This feature is currently enabled on Windows and will be deployed later for macOS and Linux as well.
The post Tab Unloading in Firefox 93 appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haik Aftandilian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tab Unloading in Firefox 93]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47413</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/10/tab-unloading-in-firefox-93/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T16:52:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starting with Firefox 93, Firefox will monitor available system memory and, should it ever become so critically low that a crash is imminent, Firefox will respond by unloading memory-heavy but not actively used tabs. This feature is currently enabled on Windows and will be deployed later for macOS and Linux as well.
The post Tab Unloading in Firefox 93 appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haik Aftandilian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[13 tiny and terrific entries from the js13kGames competition]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=60245</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2021-10-05-13-tiny-and-terrific-entries-from-the-js13kgames-competition/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T16:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you think about it, 13kB isn’t really a lot. The image above is 81kB. This page weighs over 3MB (waaay more if you include the videos). That’s why it’s so incredibly impressive that the]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lee Reilly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[9 Easy Local Link Building Tactics]]></title>
        <id>https://ahrefs.com/blog/?p=135855</id>
        <link href="https://ahrefs.com/blog/local-link-building/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T16:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ll show you nine ways to build local backlinks in this guide, but first, let’s cover the basics… What local link building is How to estimate the number of backlinks you need How to build local links Local link building…
Read more ›]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Stox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Local Testing A Serverless API (API Gateway And Lambda)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/local-testing-serverless-api-gateway-lambda/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/local-testing-serverless-api-gateway-lambda/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever struggled with testing cloud services locally? Specifically, have you ever struggled with locally testing an API that uses API Gateway and Lambda, with the Serverless framework, on AWS? In this article, Tom Hudson shares a quick overview of how easy it is to quickly set up your project to test locally before deploying to AWS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tom Hudson)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best practices for using third-party embeds]]></title>
        <id>https://web.dev/embed-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://web.dev/embed-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many sites use third-party embeds to create an engaging user experience by delegating some sections of a web page to another content provider. The most common examples of third-party content embeds are video players, social-media feeds, maps, and advertisements.
Third-party content can impact the performance of a page in many ways. It can be render-blocking, contend with other critical resources for network and bandwidth, or affect the Core Web Vitals metrics. Third-party embeds may also cause layout shifts as they load. This article discusses performance best practices that you can use when loading third-party embeds, efficient loading techniques, and the Layout Shift Terminator tool that helps reduce layout shifts for popular embeds.
What is an embed #
A third-party embed is any content …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>web.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bootstrap 5.1.2]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.getbootstrap.com/2021/10/05/bootstrap-5-1-2/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.getbootstrap.com/2021/10/05/bootstrap-5-1-2/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bootstrap v5.1.2 is here with a handful of improvements across our components, plus a fix for an issue in another project that prevented our Sass from compiling properly. Keep reading for the highlights.
Highlights
Temporarily patched a postcss-values-parser issue by rearranging our calc() functions that use negative numbers. This should restore the ability to import and compile Bootstrap’s Sass in create-react-app.
Added border-radius sizes to small and large .form-selects
Added align-self: center to buttons for improved rendering in flex containers
Fixed Collapse regression that prevented toggling between sibling children
Updated JS Sanitizer to add sms in the SAFE_URL_PATTERN
Improved docs around .img-fluid
Added role="switch" to our form switches in our docs
Implemented GitHub Issue forms to replace our previous issue templates.
Up next
Up next is our v5.2.0 release, adding more utility improvements and fixing an issue with how Sass handles re-assigned maps and variables. Alongside that, we’ll be shipping an update to v4 soon as well.
Get the release
Head to https://getbootstrap.com for the latest. It’s also been pushed to npm:
npm i bootstrap


Review the GitHub v5.1.2 release changelog for a complete list of changes since our last release.
Support the team
Visit our Open Collective page or our team members' GitHub profiles to help support the maintainers contributing to Bootstrap.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bootstrap Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new public beta of GitHub Releases: How we’re improving the release experience]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/?p=60544</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2021-10-04-beta-github-releases-improving-release-experience/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T18:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Releases has a new look and updated tools to make it easier for open source communities to create and share high-quality releases with auto-generated release notes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Myles Borins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fighting misinformation: An embedded media provenance specification]]></title>
        <id>https://www.bbc.co.uk/blogs/internet/entries/5d371e1b-54be-491f-b8ee-9e354bafb168</id>
        <link href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/blogs/internet/entries/5d371e1b-54be-491f-b8ee-9e354bafb168"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T15:51:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are looking at technology solutions to the problem of news disinformation. Here is an overview of a draft version of an embedded media provenance specification, released by the Coalition for Content Provenance and Authenticity (C2PA).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charlie Halford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[483: Q&A on XState, Getting Comfortable with JavaScript, Managing WordPress Sites, and Background Images in CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://shoptalkshow.com/?p=5173</id>
        <link href="https://shoptalkshow.com/483/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T13:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Chris says, we're back to the meat 'n potatoes of ShopTalk with a Q&A episode including: XState thoughts, getting comfortable with JavaScript, tips on managing several WordPress sites, the best method to schedule high latency tasks with Node.js, a strategy for background images in CSS, and dealing with landing pages and subpages.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ShopTalk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build An Expandable Accessible Gallery]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/build-expandable-accessible-gallery/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/build-expandable-accessible-gallery/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be looking at how to set up a gallery that is expandable as well as accessible with a few tips and tricks along the way. Let’s get started!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Silvestar Bistrović)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eating the Cloud from Outside In]]></title>
        <id>https://swyx.io/cloudflare-go</id>
        <link href="https://swyx.io/cloudflare-go"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T02:23:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AWS is playing Chess. Cloudflare is playing Go.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Swyx.io RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Platform News #41]]></title>
        <id>https://www.patreon.com/posts/56962512</id>
        <link href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/56962512"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T00:56:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read on Patreon →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Web Platform News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Chromium Chronicle #25: Thread Safety Annotations]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/chromium-chronicle-25/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/chromium-chronicle-25/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 25: by Victor Costan in SFO (October, 2021)
Previous episodes
In C++, ruling out the possibility of data races comes down to a small thread-safety correctness proof for every data member access.
These proofs add up to a lot of mental toil, especially when reviewing or refactoring code.
Clang's static analysis framework takes over the toil of thread-safety proofs.
# Add GUARDED_BY_CONTEXT() to data members in thread-unsafe classes
Most Chrome classes are thread-unsafe, and should be used on a single sequence.
Add annotations to all data members that are not thread-safe.
Unnecessary annotations are safe, but missing annotations are a risk of data races.
#include "base/sequence_checker.h"  // for SEQUENCE_CHECKER()
#include "base/thread_annotations.h"  // for GUARDED_BY_CONTEXT()
clas…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tailwind Mobile – Pixel perfect mobile UI components built with Tailwind CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28723888</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/tailwind-mobile/tailwind-mobile"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T22:05:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://github.com/tailwind-mobile/tailwind-mobile
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28723888
Points: 4
# Comments: 0]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>chuckrincon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MDN Web Docs at Write the Docs Prague 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47391</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/10/mdn-web-docs-at-write-the-docs-prague-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T12:46:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The MDN Web Docs team is pleased to sponsor Write the Docs Prague 2021, which is being held remotely this year. We’re excited to join hundreds of documentarians to learn more about collaborating with writers, developers, and readers to make better documentation. We plan to take part in all that the conference has to offer, including the Writing Day, Job Fair, and the virtual hallway track.
The post MDN Web Docs at Write the Docs Prague 2021 appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Beck</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MDN Web Docs at Write the Docs Prague 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47391</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/10/mdn-web-docs-at-write-the-docs-prague-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T12:46:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The MDN Web Docs team is pleased to sponsor Write the Docs Prague 2021, which is being held remotely this year. We’re excited to join hundreds of documentarians to learn more about collaborating with writers, developers, and readers to make better documentation. We plan to take part in all that the conference has to offer, including the Writing Day, Job Fair, and the virtual hallway track.
The post MDN Web Docs at Write the Docs Prague 2021 appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Beck</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's new in Svelte: October 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://svelte.dev/blog/whats-new-in-svelte-october-2021</id>
        <link href="https://svelte.dev/blog/whats-new-in-svelte-october-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A whole year of "What's new in Svelte"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Svelte blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Search Functionality In Your Nuxt App Using Algolia InstantSearch]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/search-functionality-nuxt-app-algolia-instantsearch/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/search-functionality-nuxt-app-algolia-instantsearch/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many websites have some sort of search feature because it helps users navigate through their content easily. Implementing it the right way can be tricky and might not give a good user experience. In this tutorial, we will be integrating Algolia, a popular and powerful search service for the best experience on our Nuxt site.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miracle Onyenma)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Notes for Safari Technology Preview 133]]></title>
        <id>https://webkit.org/blog/11975/release-notes-for-safari-technology-preview-133/</id>
        <link href="https://webkit.org/blog/11975/release-notes-for-safari-technology-preview-133/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T17:07:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Safari Technology Preview Release 133 is now available for download for macOS Big Sur and betas of macOS Monterey.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>WebKit</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Notes for Safari Technology Preview 133]]></title>
        <id>https://webkit.org/?p=11975</id>
        <link href="https://webkit.org/blog/11975/release-notes-for-safari-technology-preview-133/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T17:07:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Safari Technology Preview Release 133 is now available for download for macOS Big Sur and betas of macOS Monterey.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Blog – WebKit</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twenty years of writing on my website]]></title>
        <id>https://adactio.com/journal/18494</id>
        <link href="https://adactio.com/journal/18494"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T17:02:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On this day twenty years ago I wrote the first entry in my online journal. In the intervening two decades I’ve written a further 2,817 entries.
I am now fifty years old, which means I’ve been blogging for two fifths of my lifetime.
My website has actually been around for longer than twenty years, but its early incarnations had no blog. That all changed when I relaunched the site on September 30th, 2001.
I wrote at the time:
I’m not quite sure what I will be saying here over the coming days, weeks, months and years.
Honestly I still feel like that.
I think it’s safe to assume an “anything goes” attitude for what I post here. Being a web developer, there’s bound to be lots of geeky, techy stuff but I also want a place where I can rant and rave about life in general.
That’s been pretty true, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adactio: Journal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[7 Best Online Marketing Communities (Free and Paid) to Join in 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://ahrefs.com/blog/?p=135654</id>
        <link href="https://ahrefs.com/blog/best-marketing-communities/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T16:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[But with the wealth of groups to choose from, finding the right one to join can be overwhelming if you’re new to the space. To help, we joined some popular marketing communities and cherry-picked our favorites. Here’s what made the…
Read more ›]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Liew</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Time Of Transition (October 2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-october-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-october-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Get your desktop ready for fall and the upcoming Halloween season with a fresh batch of desktop wallpapers. Created with love by designers and artists from across the globe, they come in versions with and without a calendar for October 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Public Working Draft: Media Source Extensions™]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9265</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9265"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T07:12:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Media Working Group has published a First Public Working Draft of Media Source Extensions™. This specification extends HTMLMediaElement [HTML] to allow JavaScript to generate media streams for playback. Allowing JavaScript to generate streams facilitates a variety of use cases like adaptive streaming and time shifting live streams.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call for Review: Payment Request API and Payment Method Identifiers are W3C Proposed Recommendations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9269</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9269"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T07:10:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Web Payments Working Group has just published Proposed Recommendations of Payment Request API and Payment Method Identifiers. Payment Request standardizes an API to allow merchants (i.e., web sites selling physical or digital goods) to utilize one or more payment methods with minimal integration. Browsers facilitate the payment flow between merchant and user. Payment Method […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call for Review: ARIA in HTML is a W3C Proposed Recommendation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9272</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9272"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T07:09:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Web Applications Working Group has just published a Proposed Recommendation of ARIA in HTML. This specification defines the authoring rules (author conformance requirements) for the use of Accessible Rich Internet Applications (WAI-ARIA) 1.1 and Digital Publishing WAI-ARIA Module 1.0 attributes on [HTML] elements. This specification’s primary objective is to define requirements for use with conformance checking tools used […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress in the Privacy Sandbox (September 2021)]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/progress-in-the-privacy-sandbox-2021-09/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/progress-in-the-privacy-sandbox-2021-09/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the September edition of "Progress in the Privacy
Sandbox" tracking the milestones on the
path to phasing out third-party cookies in Chrome and working towards a more
private web. Each month we'll share an overview of the updates to the Privacy
Sandbox timeline along with news from
across the project.
Prevent covert tracking

User-agent reduction timeline published, changes start from Chrome 101
(stable in Q2 2022) and end with Chrome 113 (stable in Q2 2023)
User-agent reduction early opt-in origin trial registration opened
Strengthen cross-site privacy
boundaries

Initial origin trial for First-Party Sets concluded
DevTools cookie functionality improved
Show relevant content and ads

Extending the overall Discussion period to Q4 2021 and starting the Testing
period in Q1 2022
H…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[335: Code’s a Drag]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.codepen.io/?p=15897</id>
        <link href="https://blog.codepen.io/2021/09/29/335-codes-a-drag/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T20:33:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are lots of types of dragging that can happen on websites. While they are all click (or tap), hold down, move, and let go, they are all quite a bit different. For instance: Drag files/folders onto the browser window and drop them. The likely use case there is uploading. Drag an element on the […]
The post 335: Code’s a Drag appeared first on CodePen Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Show HN: Flowrift – Tailwind CSS UI Blocks]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28698302</id>
        <link href="https://flowrift.com"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T19:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://flowrift.com
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28698302
Points: 7
# Comments: 9]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>sergejcodes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Innovation on the Clearleft podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://adactio.com/journal/18489</id>
        <link href="https://adactio.com/journal/18489"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T13:58:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re past the halfway mark for this season of the Clearleft podcast. Episode four came out today. It’s all about innovation.
At the beginning of the episode, I think you can hear the scorn in my voice. Y’see, innovation is one of the words—like “disruptive”—that gets thrown around a lot and everyone assumes it only has positive connotations. But words like “innovative” and “disruptive” can be applied to endeavours that are not good for the world.
Bitcoin, for example, could rightly be described as innovative (and disruptive) but it’s also a planet-destroying ponzi scheme—like a lovechild of the trolley problem and the paperclip maximizer designed to generate the most amount of waste for the least amount of value.
So, yeah, I’m not a fan of innovation for innovation’s sake. But don’t worry. For this episode of the podcast I set my personal feelings to one side and let the episode act as a conduit for much smarter people.
The whole thing clocks in at 25 minutes but I think this episode might have the widest range of contributors yet. There are snippets from an internal Clearleft discussion, soundbites from a panel discussion, extracts from conference talks, as well as interviews with individuals. From Clearleft there’s Chris How, Andy Thornton, Jon Aizlewood and Lorenzo Ferronato. From the panel discussion there’s Janna Bastow, Matt Cooper-Wright, Dorota Biniecka and Akshan Ish. And from UX Fest there’s Radhika Dutt, Teresa Torres and Gregg Bernstein.
I happily defer to their expertise on this topic. Have a listen and hear what they have to say.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adactio: Journal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Modern Image Formats: AVIF And WebP]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/modern-image-formats-avif-webp/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/modern-image-formats-avif-webp/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T08:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll highlight how modern image formats (AVIF or WebP) can improve compression by up to 50% and deliver better quality per-byte while still looking visually appealing. We’ll compare what’s possible at high-quality, low-quality and file-size targets.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Addy Osmani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use Tailwind CSS to Build HTML Email Templates]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28687075</id>
        <link href="https://dev.to/ehlo_250/set-of-free-mit-transactional-email-templates-built-using-tailwind-css-4n12"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T20:26:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://dev.to/ehlo_250/set-of-free-mit-transactional-email-templates-built-using-tailwind-css-4n12
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28687075
Points: 4
# Comments: 0]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>albertgoeswoof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PPC Marketing: Beginner’s Guide to Pay-Per-Click Ads]]></title>
        <id>https://ahrefs.com/blog/?p=135731</id>
        <link href="https://ahrefs.com/blog/ppc-marketing/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T16:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Search ads are the most common ad format in PPC marketing: Display ads also fall under the PPC marketing hood (although there are different ways to buy these, other than PPC): The same applies to social media ads, like these…
Read more ›]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michal Pecánek</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halfway through season three of the Clearleft podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://adactio.com/journal/18486</id>
        <link href="https://adactio.com/journal/18486"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T13:23:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Each season of the Clearleft podcast has six episodes. Three of the six episodes of the current season are available with another three still to come.
In case you missed them, the episodes of season three released so far are:
Coaching
What’s the difference between training, coaching, and mentorship?
Design Engineering
A role that sits at the intersection—or rather, the gap—between design and engineering.
Design Research
The journey from evaluative research to generative research.
That’s quite a mixed bag. You might think that there’s no particular unifying to a season of the podcast.
Well, that’s kind of true. There’s no specific theme. But each season does have a meta-grouping.
At Clearleft, we think about our services in three interconnected categories: explore, create, and grow.
“Explore” is all about the big strategic picture.
“Create” is the nitty-gritty work of delivery.
“Grow” is what connects those together.
Each season of the podcast focuses on one of those categories. This season it’s all about “explore” with a bit of “grow” thrown in.
The next three episodes of this season will double down on the big-picture thinking. I don’t want to give any spoilers, but I’ll just remind you that if you’re not already subscribed to the Clearleft podcast, I highly recommend rectifying that situation.
Subscribe via RSS, or on Apple, Google, Spotify, or wherever you get your podcasts from.
And if you’re already subscribed …thank you. If you’re enjoying listening to it half as much as I’m enjoying making it, then I’m enjoying it twice as much as you.
Seriously though, if you like what you hear, please share it around. Drop a link to the Clearleft podcast into your work Slack channel or share it in a tweet.
Thank you for listening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adactio: Journal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DOM Review Draft Published 15 June 2020 is a W3C Recommendation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9262</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9262"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T09:48:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As part of working with the WHATWG together on HTML and DOM, W3C selected today to endorse the DOM Review Draft — Published 15 June 2020 as a W3C Recommendation. DOM defines a platform-neutral model for events, aborting activities, and node trees. For more information, see the blog post WHATWG Review Drafts of HTML and […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Accessibility Of Your Markdown]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/improving-accessibility-of-markdown/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/improving-accessibility-of-markdown/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can find Markdown in many places on the Internet. This article covers different aspects of Markdown and how it interacts with other technology.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Eric Bailey)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Public Working Draft: Synchronization Accessibility User Requirements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9260</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9260"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T08:47:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Accessible Platform Architectures Working Group has published a First Public Working Draft of Synchronization Accessibility User Requirements. This document outlines accessibility-related user needs and associated requirements for the synchronization of multimedia. The successful synchronization of multimedia content, especially audio and video, is essential to accessible web-based communication and cooperation. Understandable media is therefore media […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Set of TailwindCSS Based Transactional HTML Email Templates]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28672926</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/ohmysmtp/templates"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T16:42:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://github.com/ohmysmtp/templates
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28672926
Points: 14
# Comments: 18]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>albertgoeswoof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Partitioning GitHub’s relational databases to handle scale]]></title>
        <id>https://github.blog/2021-09-27-partitioning-githubs-relational-databases-scale/</id>
        <link href="https://github.blog/2021-09-27-partitioning-githubs-relational-databases-scale/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T16:02:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2019, to meet GitHub's growth and availability challenges, we set a plan in motion to improve our tooling and ability to partition relational databases.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Engineering – The GitHub Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[482: Asset Pipeline Issues, Google ZX, Crazy CSS, and a New CSS Reset]]></title>
        <id>https://shoptalkshow.com/?p=5147</id>
        <link href="https://shoptalkshow.com/482/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T12:48:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join us on YouTube 3x a week for more ShopTalk fun. This episode: How would you build with maximum user growth in mind? Asset pipeline issues, self provisioning runtime, Google ZX, and crazy new CSS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ShopTalk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s Dive Into Cypress For End-to-End Testing]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/cypress-end-to-end-testing/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/cypress-end-to-end-testing/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is end-to-end testing a painful topic for you? In this article, Ramona Schwering explains how to handle end-to-end testing with Cypress and make it make it not so tedious and expensive for yourself, but fun instead.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ramona Schwering)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome Web Store policy updates for Q3 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/policy-update-kwspam-and-circumvention/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/policy-update-kwspam-and-circumvention/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the years we've made a number of product and policy improvements to help ensure a quality
experience for both users and developers. As part of this work, we've updated our best practices,
and identifiednamed undesirable behaviors that create spammy experiences for users. Today, we're
furthering this work by clarifying and updating two policies, to keep the quality of extensions
high, and the experience for developers consistent:
# Keyword Spam Update
Keyword Spam is the practice of including irrelevant or excessive keywords in an extensions
description in an attempt to manipulate its ranking, resulting in a spammy, negative user
experience. We don't allow extensions with misleading, improperly formatted, non-descriptive,
irrelevant, excessive, or inappropriate metadata, including but …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome user device characteristics report]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/device-characteristics/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/device-characteristics/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Developers are constantly wondering about what kind of audience they are
developing for. Are they using high end devices with large RAM? What connection
are they using (for example Wi-Fi, 2G) and so on. The answers to these questions
can affect product development decisions such as choosing the
technologies to render the content. This report provides timeline data to inform
developers on these questions for a list of countries, such as the US, Brazil,
Japan, and others. Three platforms are included when data is available: Android,
Windows, and ChromeOS.
Looking at the data, there might be some interesting things for developers to
think about. For example, in Japan on the Android platform, the majority of
users have five to eight cores, and the prevalence is quite a bit higher than in
the US, and much higher than in next billion user (NBU) countries. Another
example: if you look at RAM on Android, a very low percentage of Brazil devices
have RAM larger than 5 GB, which is much lower than in the US, and also lower
than India. We hope publishing information like this periodically will help
developers have a better understanding of the Chrome user device
characteristics.
This data comes from usage statistics sent to Google from Chrome installations.
In Chrome, users can choose to send usage statistics and crash reports to Google
to help improve Chrome's feature set and stability. Usage statistics and crash
reports are enabled by default for Chrome consumer installs and can be disabled
during installation or in Chrome's settings. Metrics collection is pseudonymous,
and metrics are tagged by an opaque per-install identifier that is not joinable
with other datasets.  If the metrics collection is re-enabled, the unique
identifier will also be reset. We used the data collected to calculate the
various statistics in this
report.
Photo by Halacious on Unsplash]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.2]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T18:45:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: unicode characters in URL caused download error
Fixed: project root npm install error
Added: unit test library
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @CaptNo1]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beware False Negatives]]></title>
        <id>https://adrianroselli.com/?p=11860</id>
        <link href="https://adrianroselli.com/2021/09/beware-false-negatives.html"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T23:58:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Automated accessibility testing tools are rightly wary of giving false positives. You don’t want to flag something as an error in a test only to have the team rebuild an entire thing for no reason (never mind the risk of introducing errors). We know automated accessibility testing tools can really…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrian Roselli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I changed my mind about Tailwind CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28645995</id>
        <link href="https://www.thomasdhondt.be/blog/i-changed-my-mind-about-tailwind-css"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T18:19:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.thomasdhondt.be/blog/i-changed-my-mind-about-tailwind-css
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28645995
Points: 1
# Comments: 1]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>gymshoes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shop Talk Goes Video]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/09/shop-talk-goes-video/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/09/shop-talk-goes-video/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T17:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[🎉 After nearly ten years of weekly podcasts, Shop Talk has entered into a new realm: Video. Under the umbrella of the CSS-Tricks YouTube channel we’ve started posting daily-ish videos about front-end web development. This is a 🔥 year for CSS, so there’s no shortage of topics or #hotdrama to talk about and demo.
We’re still dialing in the formula, but it’s shaping up to look like 15~20 minute videos delivered thrice weekly. Math-wise, that’s not too different than doing another one hour podcast every week. Video of course is a little more involved, you need to spend a bit more effort planning out tech demos. Keeping our same (overly?) casual feel makes it all sustainable for us. If Chris and I were doing video content full time it might make sense to write and edit a bit more, but both of us have day jobs, are running companies, and contributing code.
One nice by-product of exploring video is that we get a chance to re-explain mouth-coding examples or overly visual concepts that were probably confusing on the audio podcast. As much as I love podcasting, the lack of visual examples for a visual field like Web Design and Development is a limitation. I like that the YouTube series is like supplementary material to ideas covered in the podcast, rather than a replacement.
Okay! That’s it! I hope you enjoy the little foray into video.
Watch on YouTube
And I wouldn’t be a YouTuber if I didn’t say… Be sure to drop a like and subscribe, that really helps us out in the algorithm. And ring that bell for notifications when new videos come out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rebuilding A Large E-Commerce Website With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/lessons-learned-ecommerce-nextjs-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/lessons-learned-ecommerce-nextjs-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We made the switch from a more traditional integrated e-commerce platform to a headless platform with Next.js. Here are the most important lessons learned while rebuilding a large e-commerce site with Next.js.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jonne Kats)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Online Workshop: Frustrating Design Patterns And How To Fix Them]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/smashing-workshop-frustrating-design-patterns/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/smashing-workshop-frustrating-design-patterns/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T06:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’ve seen them before. Confusing and frustrating design patterns that seem to be chasing you everywhere you go, from one website to another. It’s time to fix them for good in a [free Smashing online workshop](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/workshops/vitaly-friedman-frustrating-patterns/) next week.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Show HN: Demo of Tailwind CSS, Gulpjs, Alpine.js (Version 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28637327</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/joelparkerhenderson/demo-tailwind-css"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T00:36:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://github.com/joelparkerhenderson/demo-tailwind-css
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28637327
Points: 5
# Comments: 0]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jph</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bringing instant page-loads to the browser through speculative prerendering]]></title>
        <id>https://web.dev/speculative-prerendering/</id>
        <link href="https://web.dev/speculative-prerendering/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Resource hints, such as preconnect,
preload,
prefetch, and
prerender, help
the browser figure out which resources will the user need in the near future.
preconnect and preload are declarative hints—the browser must act on
them, so use them when you are sure that a resource will be required during the
next load.
prefetch and prerender are speculative hints—use these to recommend that
the browser should fetch a certain resource because there's a high chance it
might be required.
This article focuses on speculative prefetching and prerendering. Learn more about
how they're used, the drawbacks of the current implementations, and popular external
libraries that implement sophisticated speculation. Enhancements that bring same-origin
speculative prerendering to the browser are under development …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>web.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Demand Generation 101: 5 Strategies That Work]]></title>
        <id>https://ahrefs.com/blog/?p=135621</id>
        <link href="https://ahrefs.com/blog/demand-generation-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T16:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We currently rank #1 for this term (and many others) with our free backlink checker: This helps to generate demand for our products because our free backlink checker is a free version of our premium tool. In this guide, you’ll…
Read more ›]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Holly Stanley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All things are possible with code, but not everything is beneficial]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/09/all-things-possible-not-everything-beneficial/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/09/all-things-possible-not-everything-beneficial/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T15:49:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In my weird role as hybrid contractor/consultant I get asked, “Is it possible to do {{some_feature}}?” and what goes through my head is a bastardized version of the Apostle Paul saying:
All things are possible (with code), but not everything is beneficial.
The answer to “Can you make {{feature}} with code?” is almost always “Yes.” Given infinite time, infinite budget, infinite lines of code, and infinite opportunities for failure; I’m almost certain we can come up with a working solution for any scenario you can dream up. There’s JavaScript in space, I’m sure we can figure out your idea.
Now does it work for the user? Would it explode the timeline and scope? Does it add an immense amount of complexity and technical debt? Would it tear the social fabric of American democracy in the process?…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Content Model Is Not a Design System]]></title>
        <id>https://alistapart.com/article/a-content-model-is-not-a-design-system/</id>
        <link href="https://alistapart.com/article/a-content-model-is-not-a-design-system/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you remember when having a great website was enough? Now, people are getting answers from Siri, Google search snippets, and mobile apps, not just our websites. Forward-thinking organizations have adopted an omnichannel content strategy, whose mission is to reach audiences across multiple digital channels and platforms.
But how do you set up a content management system (CMS) to reach your audience now and in the future? I learned the hard way that creating a content model—a definition of content types, attributes, and relationships that let people and systems understand content—with my more familiar design-system thinking would capsize my customer’s omnichannel content strategy. You can avoid that outcome by creating content models that are semantic and that also connect related content.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>by</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simplifying Form Styles With `accent-color`]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/simplifying-form-styles-accent-color/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/simplifying-form-styles-accent-color/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new CSS `accent-color` property makes it quick and easy to roll out our brand colors to certain form inputs by leveraging user agent styles. In this article we’ll take a look at what it does and how to use it alongside `color-scheme` for simple, accessible checkboxes and radio buttons — and imagine how we might use it in the future.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Michelle Barker)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Show HN: A Tool to Rapidly Prototype and Build Webpages Using Tailwind CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28626065</id>
        <link href="https://www.devwares.com/windframe"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T07:07:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.devwares.com/windframe
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28626065
Points: 3
# Comments: 1]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>overwatch02</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Notion Blogging Kanban]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/09/my-notion-blogging-kanban/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/09/my-notion-blogging-kanban/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T00:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Six years ago, I started a good blogging habit of writing down any idea I had as a draft post. This was a good practice because the idea was now out of my head and I wouldn’t stay up at night thinking about it. Over time that grew to about eighty posts in different states of completeness and it became overwhelming. 16,000+ words, terribly organized.
A flat folder full of alphabetically sorted markdown files was not intuitively useful. I had no idea which posts were most recent, which were almost done, and which needed to go away. Lots of those drafts were a zingy title and a vague one-liner of text. Reverse engineering my own ideas when I revisited them later was difficult. It became mentally taxing to manage my own blog.
In a fit of desperation, I took my posts one step away from “the met…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The transition of Chrome extensions to Manifest V3]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/mv2-transition/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/mv2-transition/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this year, for Chrome 88, we announced the availability of a new manifest
version for the
Chrome extension ecosystem. Years in the making, Manifest V3 is more secure, performant, and
privacy-preserving than its predecessor. It is an evolution of the extension platform that takes
into consideration both the changing web landscape and the future of browser extensions.
As we look to the future by continuing to iterate on and improve upon Manifest V3 functionality, we
also want to share details about the plan to phase out Manifest V2 extensions.
There are two key dates for the phase-out:
January 17, 2022: New Manifest V2 extensions will no longer be accepted by the Chrome Web
Store. Developers may still push updates to existing Manifest V2 extensions, but no new Manifest
V2 items may b…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deprecations and removals in Chrome 95]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/deps-rems-95/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/deps-rems-95/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit ChromeStatus.com for lists of current deprecations and previous removals.
Chrome 95 beta was released on September 23, 2021 and is expected to become the
stable version in late October, 2021.
# FTP support removed
Chrome is removing support for FTP
URLs. Use of FTP in the
browser is sufficiently low that it is no longer viable to invest in improving
the existing FTP client. In addition, more capable FTP clients are available on
all affected platforms.
Google Chrome 72 and later removed support for fetching document subresources
over FTP and rendering of top level FTP resources. Currently navigating to FTP
URLs results in showing a directory listing or a download depending on the type
of resource. A bug in Google Chrome 74 and later resulted in dropping support for
accessing FTP URLs …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kustomer Is Hiring]]></title>
        <id>https://benmccormick.org/2021/09/23/kustomer-is-hiring</id>
        <link href="https://benmccormick.org/2021/09/23/kustomer-is-hiring"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ben McCormick's blog on JavaScript and Web Development]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ben@benmccormick.org (Ben McCormick)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[334: Custom Properties]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.codepen.io/?p=15889</id>
        <link href="https://blog.codepen.io/2021/09/22/334-custom-properties/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T19:13:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chris & Shaw talk about a big ol’ conversion to getting CodePen’s color system to use --custom-properties all the way through, rather than Sass variables. Why? All sorts of reasons, kinda boiling down to the fact that they are just better. Here’s a tiny one: you can use the Web Inspector and see what some […]
The post 334: Custom Properties appeared first on CodePen Blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Your `head` Straight: A New CSS Performance Diagnostics Snippet]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/css-head-tag/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/css-head-tag/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We love little useful tools and techniques to help folks get their work done better and faster. Today, we’d love to shine the spotlights on a little helper that helps spot common performance bottlenecks easily: [ct.css](https://csswizardry.com/ct/).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[(Neo)vim tips and tricks: Volume One]]></title>
        <id>https://benfrain.com/?p=4361</id>
        <link href="https://benfrain.com/neovim-tips-and-tricks-volume-one/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T12:02:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intro Want the YouTube version? I flip back and forth between editors. Usually I'm in Sublime but I'm back using NeoVim for the last few weeks. Subsequently, I've picked up a few things using it, and being back in the Terminal full time, that I thought would be worth sharing. Copying/Moving lines to marks There's […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Frain</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Design research on the Clearleft podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://adactio.com/journal/18474</id>
        <link href="https://adactio.com/journal/18474"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T08:49:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re halfway through the third season of the Clearleft podcast already!
Episode three is all about design research. I like the narrative structure of this. It’s a bit like a whodunnit, but it’s more like a whydunnit. The “why” question is “why aren’t companies hiring more researchers?”
The scene of the crime is this year’s UX Fest, where talks by both Teresa Torres and Gregg Bernstein uncovered the shocking lack of researchers. From there, I take up the investigation with Maite Otondo and Stephanie Troeth.
I won’t spoil it but by the end there’s an answer to the mystery.
I learned a lot along the way too. I realised how many axes of research there are. There’s qualitative research (stories, emotion, and context) and then there’s quantitative research (volume and data). But there’s also evualative research (testing a hyphothesis) and generative research (exploring a problem space before creating a solution). By my count that gives four possible combos: qualitative evaluative research, quantitative evaluative research, qualitative generative research, and quantitative generative research. Phew!
Steph was a terrific guest. Only a fraction of our conversation made it into the episode, but we chatted for ages.
And Maite kind of blew my mind too, especially when she was talking about the relationship between research and design and she said:
Research is about the present and design is about the future.
🤯
I’m going to use that quote again in a future episode. In fact, this episode on design research leads directly into the next two episodes. You won’t want to miss them. So if you’re not already subscribed to the Clearleft podcast, you should get on that, whether it’s via the RSS feed, Apple, Google, Spotify, Overcast, or wherever you get your podcasts from.
Have a listen to this episode on design research and if you’re a researcher yourself, remember that unlike most companies we value research at Clearleft and that’s why we’re hiring another researcher right now. Come and work with us!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adactio: Journal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[6 Risky Black Hat SEO Tactics to Avoid in 2021 (And Their White Hat Alternatives)]]></title>
        <id>https://ahrefs.com/blog/?p=135595</id>
        <link href="https://ahrefs.com/blog/black-hat-seo-tactics/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T22:15:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[That’s why some business owners resort to black-hat tactics to topple competitors from the top of the SERPs. While there are some black-hat SEO tactics you clearly shouldn’t use, like hacking (because it’s illegal), others seem less risky. But even…
Read more ›]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joshua Hardwick</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Streaming Euro 2020 live at a record new scale]]></title>
        <id>https://www.bbc.co.uk/blogs/internet/entries/fe629b38-57af-49c8-8922-352174101511</id>
        <link href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/blogs/internet/entries/fe629b38-57af-49c8-8922-352174101511"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T13:38:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[During the 2018 World Cup quarter final our systems at the time became overwhelmed, leading to a major outage. How did we scale our live streaming architecture to stream the Euro 2020 final online to a new record of 7.1 million viewers?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pierre-Yves Bigourdan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build Your Own Mouseless Development Environment]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/mouseless-development-environment/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/mouseless-development-environment/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building a development environment with the shell as a keystone offers multiple benefits. You can customize everything depending on your own needs, and the biggest of all, you can control your entire development environment with your keyboard.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Matthieu Cneude)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Public Working Draft: WebRTC Encoded Transform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9258</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9258"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T11:19:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Web Real-Time Communications Working Group has published a First Public Working Draft of WebRTC Encoded Transform. The goal of this work is to define an API for processing encoded media in WebRTC, for example for voice processing, background removal, dynamic control of codec parameters, etc. This document specifies an API surface for manipulating the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Coralie Mercier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Web Development Tools Are Helping Users Keep Pace With Rapid Change]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/web-development-tools-users-keep-pace-rapid-change/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/web-development-tools-users-keep-pace-rapid-change/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The last 18 months have been a time of unprecedented turbulence. As the people of the world have flooded online, businesses have joined them, using web development tools to adapt in real-time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An update on the accessibility of conditionally revealed questions]]></title>
        <id>https://accessibility.blog.gov.uk/2021/09/21/an-update-on-the-accessibility-of-conditionally-revealed-questions/</id>
        <link href="https://accessibility.blog.gov.uk/2021/09/21/an-update-on-the-accessibility-of-conditionally-revealed-questions/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T09:04:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GOV.UK Design System is improving radio buttons and checkboxes that conditionally reveal fields to make them more accessible. This post provides an update on our work and research.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Accessibility in government</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New in Chrome 94]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/new-in-chrome-94/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/new-in-chrome-94/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's what you need to know:
The default color space for <canvas> elements is
now formally defined  in the spec as SRGB, and you can change it to
Display P3.
WebCodecs is a new, low level way to access built in audio and
video codecs, important for streaming games, video editors, and such.
WebGPU starts its origin trial.
The PWA Summit is coming up October 6-7.
And there's plenty more.
I'm Pete LePage, working, and shooting
from home, let's dive in and see what's new for developers in Chrome 94.
# Default color space for canvas elements
How color is rendered on screen is critical to some users. For photographers,
print illustrators, and many others, the colors on screen need to match what's
printed. Starting in Chrome 94, <canvas> elements are fully color managed
using sRGB. Previously, s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why do Webdevs keep trying to kill REST?]]></title>
        <id>https://swyx.io/client-server-battle</id>
        <link href="https://swyx.io/client-server-battle"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T14:46:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How I broke out of the tiresome REST vs GraphQL debate - by realizing that the real battle is between Smart Clients and Smart Servers!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Swyx.io RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Platform Weekly #40]]></title>
        <id>https://www.patreon.com/posts/56383553</id>
        <link href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/56383553"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T14:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read on Patreon →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Web Platform News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[481: Frontend Feud: ShopTalk vs Syntax]]></title>
        <id>https://shoptalkshow.com/?p=5127</id>
        <link href="https://shoptalkshow.com/481/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T13:25:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Crossover! Your favorite web dev podcasts join forces for a super collab that’ll knock you frontend off! Amelia joins Chris Coyier and Dave Rupert from ShopTalk Show while Divya teams up with Wes Bos & Scott Tolinski from Syntax. Let the FEUDing begin!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ShopTalk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Imposter Domains Re-Publishing Your Website?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/imposter-domains-republishing-website/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/imposter-domains-republishing-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Content scraping is a fact of life on the Internet. When you think of web scraping, you probably do not think about the scrapers turning around and immediately serving your entire, whole page content on another website. But what if your site content is being re-published?  It might be already happening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ken Harker)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IndieWeb Avatar, yet another Eleventy Image Service API]]></title>
        <id>https://www.zachleat.com/web/indieweb-avatar/</id>
        <link href="https://www.zachleat.com/web/indieweb-avatar/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Eleventy API ecosystem is growing (again).
Screenshots
Sparklines
And now, avatars.
I use Twitter avatars everywhere. They require an Twitter Developer account and an API key to implement. They require the talent being pictured to have a Twitter account (not everyone does). I wanted a more open alternative. I decided to build a little image service that would fetch the icon from any web site, optimize it using Eleventy Image, and return that instead.
Demo #
     
If you want a live demo in the wild, check out the Eleventy Leaderboards (via Speedlify).
Source Code #
https://github.com/11ty/api-indieweb-avatar
Only one path parameter is supported right now: /[url]/ (must be encoded via e.g. encodeURIComponent)
My version is running on https://v1.indieweb-avatar.11ty.dev/ using the same versioning via Netlify Branch Subdomains strategy as the screenshot and sparkline services.
It makes use of Netlify’s On-Demand Builders to reduce the number of external HTTP requests to generate the images.
Deploy your own #]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zach Leatherman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's New In DevTools (Chrome 95)]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/new-in-devtools-95/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/new-in-devtools-95/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Interested in helping improve DevTools? Sign up to participate in Google User Research here.
# New CSS length authoring tools
DevTools added an easier yet flexible way to update lengths in CSS!
In the Styles pane, look for any CSS property with length (e.g. height, padding).
Hover over the unit type, and notice the unit type is underlined. Click on it to select a unit type from the dropdown.
          
Hover over the unit value, and your mouse pointer is changed to horizontal cursor. Drag horizontally to increase or decrease the value. To adjust the value by 10, hold the Shift key when dragging.
          
You can still edit the unit value as text — just click on the value and start editing.
          
Chromium issues: 1126178, 1172993
# Hide issues in the Issues tab
You can now hide speci…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Create HTML Emails with TailwindCSS]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28582415</id>
        <link href="https://maizzle.com/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-19T07:31:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://maizzle.com/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28582415
Points: 1
# Comments: 0]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>albertgoeswoof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>