<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://praveenjuge.github.io/feed-reader/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-10-15T07:13:52.091Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://praveenjuge.github.io/feed-reader/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://praveenjuge.github.io/feed-reader/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's the actual best floor planning tool I can play around with for redoing my office? Hard to find the good stuff, this whole category is SEO'd into oblivion 😅]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1448811803077656580#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1448811803077656580#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T00:43:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What's the actual best floor planning tool I can play around with for redoing my office? Hard to find the good stuff, this whole category is SEO'd into oblivion 😅]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[React.useEffect Hook – Common Problems and How to Fix Them]]></title>
        <id>61686f8b80d82d07c45a4e4a</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/most-common-react-useeffect-problems-and-how-to-fix-them/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T22:07:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[React hooks have been around for a while now. Most developers have gotten pretty comfortable with how they work and their common use cases. But there is one useEffect gotcha that a lot of us keep falling for. The use caseLet's start with a simple scenario. We are building a]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Had some major strategic breakthroughs this week, really excited about what’s next after Tailwind CSS v3.0 🤩]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1448771844929163266#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1448771844929163266#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T22:04:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Had some major strategic breakthroughs this week, really excited about what’s next after Tailwind CSS v3.0 🤩]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone Downloads Folder – Where are my Downloads? iOS and iPad]]></title>
        <id>615d559e0d91c9077974d3ec</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/iphone-downloads-folder-where-are-my-downloads-ios-and-ipad/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T21:59:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone and iPad both have an app called Files where you can locate all of your files from services including iCloud Drive, Dropbox, and more.  If you want to access the Downloads folder, you can find it inside the Files app. In this article, I will show you how to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Get into BIOS in Windows 10 – BIOS Setup PC Guide]]></title>
        <id>6167f81c80d82d07c45a4630</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-get-into-bios-in-windows-10-bios-setup-pc-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T21:03:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BIOS stands for Basic Input/Output System. It is embedded into computers as a motherboard chip and is primarily responsible for booting the computer system.  Apart from booting up your computer, BIOS is responsible for a lot of other functionality behind the scenes – like managing data flow between an operating]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Make an NFT in 14 Lines of Code]]></title>
        <id>6163d60c804854468fda82ca</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-make-an-nft/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T17:49:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[High-profile celebrities like Jay-Z and Snoop Dog are getting into NFTs. With the cheapest CryptoPunk selling for 103 ETH (~360,000 USD at the time of this article), it is an excellent time for us developers to learn more about the engineering behind them to start building things. At the]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Start an Open Source Project on GitHub – Tips from Building My Trending Repo]]></title>
        <id>615da5e40d91c9077974dd6a</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-start-an-open-source-project-on-github-tips-from-building-my-trending-repo/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T17:09:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Developers around the world use GitHub to share their projects with the global developer community.  In this article, I'll give you some opinionated tips to help you build a great open-source project you can start using. You can also use these tips for building hackathon projects. Quite recently I ended]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rotate Screen in Windows 10 – How to Flip Your Monitor Orientation 90 Degrees]]></title>
        <id>6162db83804854468fda7b4c</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/rotate-screen-in-windows-10-how-to-flip-your-monitor-orientation-90-degrees/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T15:39:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Windows 10 has a built-in feature that lets you flip or rotate your monitor screen just like you can do on your smartphone.  In this article, I will show you how to flip or rotate the monitor of your Windows 10 machine in several orientations such as reverse-landscape, portrait, and]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build Four Node.js and Express.js Projects]]></title>
        <id>61683f7180d82d07c45a4893</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-six-node-js-and-express-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T15:05:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Node.js and Express.js are popular technologies used for JavaScript backend web development. We just released a 10-hour course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will show you how to create four projects using Node and Express. John Smilga developed this course. John is one of the more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Different Degrees of Custom Property Usage]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353057</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/different-degrees-of-custom-property-usage/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T14:35:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One way to work with Custom Properties is to think of them as design tokens. Colors, spacings, fonts, and whatnot. You set them at the root of the page and use them throughout your CSS. Very useful, and the classic …
The post Different Degrees of Custom Property Usage appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Embedded Analytics Made Simple With Cumul.io Integrations]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353243</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/embedded-analytics-made-simple-with-cumul-io-integrations/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T14:32:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[(This is a sponsored post.)
Browse through SaaS communities on Twitter, LinkedIn, Reddit, Discord, you name it and you’ll see a common theme appear in many of them. That theme can go by many names: BI, analytics, insights and …
The post Embedded Analytics Made Simple With Cumul.io Integrations appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cumul.io</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Was it easier to build websites a decade ago?]]></title>
        <id>https://gomakethings.com/was-it-easier-to-build-websites-a-decade-ago/</id>
        <link href="https://gomakethings.com/was-it-easier-to-build-websites-a-decade-ago/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week, Tim McNamara tweeted:
 Why is it harder to make a website in 2021 than it was in 1996?
I mean, writing your own HTML in Notepad and uploading it via FTP was a chore. But it was understandable and easy.
If you want to create a fanpage of some obscure topic, everything is just … too much. So instead, people will create an Instagram/TikTok/Facebook/etc and start posting there.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Go Make Things</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[W3C and Yubico offer first online Web Authentication course for developers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9282</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9282"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T13:13:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[W3C and Yubico announced today the opening of registration for a W3Cx online education course that teaches developers how to build and incorporate modern authentication techniques into their web-based applications using W3C’s Web Authentication (WebAuthn). Both organizations collaborated to design the Massive Open Online Course (MOOC) titled “Introduction to Web Authentication” to equip learners with […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Coralie Mercier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smart CSS Solutions For Common UI Challenges]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/modern-css-solutions-for-common-problems/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/modern-css-solutions-for-common-problems/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing CSS has probably never been more fun and exciting than it is today. In this post we’ll take a look at common problems and use cases we all have to face in our work and how to solve them with modern CSS. If you’re interested, we’ve also just recently covered [CSS auditing tools](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/03/css-auditing-tools/), [CSS generators](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/03/css-generators/), [front-end boilerplates](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/) and [VS code extensions](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/) — you might find them useful, too.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Public Working Draft: Accessibility of Remote Meetings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9286</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9286"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T07:46:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Accessible Platform Architectures Working Group has published a First Public Working Draft of Accessibility of Remote Meetings. Remote meeting is an umbrella term used to describe real-time discussions or presentations held between two or more parties online. The issues faced by people with disabilities will vary depending on the implementation of accessibility requirements and […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[R to @adamwathan: Okay for real how do you set this room up to look nice? Only criteria is I need my work desk, somewhere to show off some books, and somewhere to play Rocket League on my PS4. Everything else in the room can go if needed!

Bonus for considering how it’d look live streaming 🤔]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1448436617375539206#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1448436617375539206#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T23:52:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Okay for real how do you set this room up to look nice? Only criteria is I need my work desk, somewhere to show off some books, and somewhere to play Rocket League on my PS4. Everything else in the room can go if needed!

Bonus for considering how it’d look live streaming 🤔]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bonsai Browser]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353719</id>
        <link href="https://bonsaibrowser.com/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T22:50:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-browser for research that helps programmers think clearly.
With Bonsai, rather than being like, I’m going to go use my web browser now, you hit Option + Space and it brings up a browser. It’s either full-screen or a …
The post Bonsai Browser appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Virtual Private Cloud Course]]></title>
        <id>6167483480d82d07c45a445f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/amazon-virtual-private-cloud-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T21:00:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Virtual Private Cloud is a service that lets you launch AWS resources in a logically isolated virtual network that you define. You get complete control over the networking environment including IP address ranges, subnets, routing, firewalls and more. We just released a full course about Amazon Virtual Private Cloud]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a Responsive Form with Filter Functionality Using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript]]></title>
        <id>616706d380d82d07c45a422b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-a-responsive-filterable-form-with-css-and-javascript/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T20:54:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most sites that display a list of data in a table typically have some kind of filter functionality implemented. This helps the user filter relevant items based on the text they type into the form input. In this quick tutorial, we are going to build a responsive filterable table which]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Object Oriented Programming With Python]]></title>
        <id>6168835180d82d07c45a4ee2</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-object-oriented-programming-with-python/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T19:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Object Oriented Programming is an important concept in software development.  Object Oriented Programming (OOP) is a programming paradigm that relies on the concept of classes and objects. You can use this method of writing programs in many programming languages, including Python We just published a complete Object Oriented Programming in]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Graphics Card Do I Have? How to Check Your GPU in Windows 10 [PC GUIDE]]]></title>
        <id>6166934680d82d07c45a3e48</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-graphics-card-do-i-have-how-to-check-your-gpu-in-windows-10-pc-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T17:01:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every computer has a graphics card that handles the rendering of every pixel you see on the monitor. This graphics card also plays a crucial role in displaying videos, running applications, and most especially, handling video game graphics.  Computers also have a graphics processing unit (GPU), which renders images and]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dart in 100 Seconds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NrO0CJCbYLA</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NrO0CJCbYLA"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T16:53:20.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Fireship</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firebase Cloud Firestore – Database Crash Course]]></title>
        <id>615855ad4aa03507d9411890</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/firebase-firestore-crash-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T15:57:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we will be learning about one of Firebase's build products called Cloud Firestore. It lets you store, sync, and retrieve data in a document-based database.  We'll learn how to set up our project for the web. Since this isn't a design-focused tutorial, we'll just use an HTML]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS is Going Gosh-Darned Hog Wild, I Tell Ya What]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352459</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/css-is-going-gosh-darned-hog-wild-i-tell-ya-what/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T15:36:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As someone just sittin’ back watching CSS evolve, it feels like we’re at one of the hottest moments of innovation in CSS history. It was really something when we got flexbox across all browsers, and not terribly long after, grid. …
The post CSS is Going Gosh-Darned Hog Wild, I Tell Ya What appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Less Absolute Positioning With Modern CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353700</id>
        <link href="https://ishadeed.com/article/less-absolute-positioning-modern-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T14:42:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ahmad Shadeed blogs the sentiment that we might not need to lean on position: absolute as much as we might have in the past. For one thing: stacking elements. For example, if you have a stack of elements that should …
The post Less Absolute Positioning With Modern CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vanilla JS Academy for Teams]]></title>
        <id>https://gomakethings.com/vanilla-js-academy-for-teams/</id>
        <link href="https://gomakethings.com/vanilla-js-academy-for-teams/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two years ago, I launched a project-based online JavaScript workshop call the Vanilla JS Academy.
I’d heard from so many people who understood the basics of JS, but struggled to put this pieces together to build actual projects. The program was specifically designed to help students get better at that, and learn how to use JavaScript to solve problems.
It quickly became my most popular product.
Over 600 people have attended the Vanilla JS Academy in the last two years.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Go Make Things</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Podcast on Running a Podcast]]></title>
        <id>dee06b78-2566-423b-be17-aea824e29569</id>
        <link href="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/syntax/Syntax396.mp3"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Syntax, Scott and Wes talk about running a podcast — recording, sponsoring, where to start, and more!
 Freshbooks - Sponsor
  Get a 30 day free trial of Freshbooks at freshbooks.com/syntax and put SYNTAX in the “How did you hear about us?” section.
  LogRocket - Sponsor
  LogRocket lets you replay what users do on your site, helping you reproduce bugs and fix issues faster. It’s an exception tracker, a session re-player and a performance monitor. Get 14 days free at logrocket.com/syntax.
  Cloudinary - Sponsor
   Cloudinary is the best way to manage images and videos in the cloud. Edit and transform for any use case, from performance to personalization, using Cloudinary’s APIs, SDKs, widgets, and integrations.
  Show Notes
  01:45 - Recording Setup
  
 Zoom to chat
  Rec…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Syntax - Tasty Web Development Treats</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated Candidate Recommendation: Media Capture and Streams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9280</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9280"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T11:37:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The WebRTC Working Group invites implementation of an updated Candidate Recommendation Snapshot of Media Capture and Streams. This document defines a set of JavaScript APIs that allow local media, including audio and video, to be requested from a platform. Comments are welcome via the GitHub issues by 13 November 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upcoming Live Workshops On Front-End & UX (Oct 2021&ndash;Jan 2022)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/new-smashing-online-workshops-oct-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/new-smashing-online-workshops-oct-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you like a good interface design challenge? What about accessibility testing and design systems? Or maybe Next.js and advanced CSS? With our new online workshops on front-end & design, we cover all of it. Ah, and [here's what our workshops are like](https://vimeo.com/616485526).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Add a Flawless Database Hook to Your React Projects]]></title>
        <id>615e276e0d91c9077974e6ba</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/add-a-database-hook-to-react-and-react-native/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T21:17:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IntroductionReact is one of the best libraries for creating stateful interfaces, and is an essential part of the internet as we know it.  Many web apps including Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, and Airbnb depend on this library to deliver stateful, cross-platform applications to billions of users. It continues to be one]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zoom Screen Sharing – How to Share My Screen on Zoom [Solved]]]></title>
        <id>61642329804854468fda8506</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/zoom-screen-sharing-how-to-share-my-screen-on-zoom-solved/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T20:53:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As more and more people are working remotely, online meeting services like Zoom are becoming more popular and widely-used.  And if you're in a Zoom meeting, you'll probably have to show your work to your co-workers from time to time.  Zoom offers many features that make sharing your screen fast]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Add Form Validation in React Forms using React Hook Form]]></title>
        <id>61612118804854468fda6b2b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/add-form-validation-in-react-app-with-react-hook-form/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T20:52:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Creating forms with proper validation can be tough and problematic. But in this blog post, I will show you how to do so in a simple and straightforward way.  We'll learn how to add validation in a form using React and React Hook Form. How to Create a Form in]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Copy and Paste on a Computer [Windows PC Keyboard Shortcut Guide]]]></title>
        <id>616478dc804854468fda89eb</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-copy-and-paste-on-a-computer-windows-pc-keyboard-shortcut-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T15:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you're working on your computer, you want to do things as quickly as possible. And you probably don't want to repeat typing the same thing over and over again.  Knowing how to copy and paste text and other data will help you work efficiently without repeating yourself.  So in]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux AWK Command – Linux and Unix Usage Syntax Examples]]></title>
        <id>61604b37804854468fda625c</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-linux-awk-command-linux-and-unix-usage-syntax-examples/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T15:34:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this beginner-friendly guide, you'll learn the very basics of the awk command. You'll also see some of the ways you can use it when dealing with text.  Let's get started!  What is the awk command? awk is a scripting language, and it is helpful when working in the command]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Make a Video Game – Create Your Own Game From Scratch Tutorial]]></title>
        <id>615d55dc0d91c9077974d404</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-make-a-video-game-create-your-own-game-from-scratch-tutorial/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T15:34:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Game development is a popular field within the software industry. But what does it take to start building games from scratch? In this article, I will talk about the different game engines and tools that you can use to build your own games. I will also provide you with dozens]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rust in 100 Seconds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5C_HPTJg5ek</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5C_HPTJg5ek"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T15:24:43.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Fireship</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What if… you could use Visual Studio Code as the editor of in-browser Developer Tools?]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=6972</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2021/10/12/what-if-you-could-use-visual-studio-code-as-the-editor-of-in-browser-developer-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T15:21:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starting with the next version of Microsoft Edge, we are running an experiment that allows you to use Visual Studio Code as the editor of the in-browser Developer Tools. Here’s a three minute video explaining why we think this is a good idea. Developer Tools have excellent visual tools that allow you to tweak and […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jamstack Developers’ Favorite Frameworks of 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353415</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/jamstack-developers-favorite-frameworks-of-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T14:30:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Which new framework should I learn this year? Is it time to ditch my CMS? What tools should I pick up if I want to scale my site to an audience of millions? The 2021 Jamstack Community Survey is here …
The post Jamstack Developers’ Favorite Frameworks of 2021 appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laurie Voss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Function expressions vs. function declarations revisisted]]></title>
        <id>https://gomakethings.com/function-expressions-vs.-function-declarations-revisisted/</id>
        <link href="https://gomakethings.com/function-expressions-vs.-function-declarations-revisisted/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Four years ago, I wrote the difference between function expressions and function declarations. Since writing that article, I’ve both changed my approach to writing functions and expanded my explanation to capture the nuance of hoisting in JavaScript.
Today, I wanted to share my updated thoughts on writing functions. Lets dig in!
What’s the difference between function expressions and function declarations? There have historically been two ways to write a function.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Go Make Things</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WooCommerce + Google Analytics]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353317</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/woocommerce-google-analytics/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T14:28:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google Analytics is powerful analytics software. A common way to use it is to just slap the JavaScript snippet on every page template you have and let it collect basic data about unique visitors and pageviews and such. That’s  useful, …
The post WooCommerce + Google Analytics appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RT by @adamwathan: Wow, I did not expect to see this one. It’s true – we love Tailwind here. ❤️ IMO its ease of use, straightforward customization, and most importantly utility class approach have helped us punch far above our weight for our team size.]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/Mike_Flores23/status/1447900011350482947#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/Mike_Flores23/status/1447900011350482947#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T12:20:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wow, I did not expect to see this one. It’s true – we love Tailwind here. ❤️ IMO its ease of use, straightforward customization, and most importantly utility class approach have helped us punch far above our weight for our team size.
nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1447545526451376128#m]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@Mike_Flores23</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful React APIs For Building Flexible Components With TypeScript]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/react-apis-building-flexible-components-typescript/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/react-apis-building-flexible-components-typescript/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[React with JSX is a fantastic tool for making easy-to-use components. Typescript components make it an absolute pleasure for developers to integrate your components into their apps and explore your APIs. Learn about three lesser-known React APIs that can take your components to the next level, and help you build even better React Components in this article.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Gaurav Khanna)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bridging The Gap Between Designers And Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/bridging-gap-between-designers-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/bridging-gap-between-designers-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UXPin has recently launched a new feature called “Merge”. This tool aims to break through the chasms of design and development, all while improving the agility and quality our teams expect. This new technology may cause some rethink on how the whole design team and engineering team collaborates.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Matthew Talebi)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Public Working Draft: Natural Language Interface Accessibility User Requirements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9275</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9275"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T08:36:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Accessible Platform Architectures Working Group has published a First Public Working Draft of Natural Language Interface Accessibility User Requirements. This document outlines various accessibility-related user needs, requirements and scenarios for natural language interfaces. These user needs should influence accessibility requirements in various related specifications, as well as the design of applications that include natural […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[W3C Invites Implementations of CSS Multi-column Layout Module Level 1]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9277</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9277"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T08:34:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CSS Working Group has published the CSS Multi-column Layout Module Level 1 as a W3C Candidate Recommendation Snapshot. This specification describes multi-column layouts in CSS, a style sheet language for the web. Using functionality described in the specification, content can be flowed into multiple columns with a gap and a rule between them. The […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Those “Get The App” Banners]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352907</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/those-get-the-app-banners/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T22:12:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why would a company promote a native app over their perfectly usable website?
We’d have to ask them, I suppose. But it’s hard not to see this push to native as a matter of priorities: that these companies consider native 
…
The post Those “Get The App” Banners appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I learned to stop worrying and love TailwindCSS]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28833449</id>
        <link href="https://blog.ohmysmtp.com/blog/why-i-use-tailwindcss/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T21:42:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://blog.ohmysmtp.com/blog/why-i-use-tailwindcss/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28833449
Points: 8
# Comments: 2]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>albertgoeswoof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cash (Tiny jQuery Alternative)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353431</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/cash-tiny-jquery-alternative/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T20:28:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The README for Cash is straightforward:
Cash is an absurdly small jQuery alternative for modern browsers (IE11+) that provides jQuery-style syntax for manipulating the DOM. Utilizing modern browser features to minimize the codebase, developers can use the familiar chainable methods 
…
The post Cash (Tiny jQuery Alternative) appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Show HN: Gust – Tailwind CSS for WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28832456</id>
        <link href="https://www.getgust.com/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T20:09:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.getgust.com/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28832456
Points: 1
# Comments: 0]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>mdsas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transitional apps]]></title>
        <id>https://gomakethings.com/transitional-apps/</id>
        <link href="https://gomakethings.com/transitional-apps/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rich Harris, the guy who created Svelte (learn more about compilers here), gave a talk at Jamstack Conf last week, and its one of the best talks I’ve ever seen.
Rich dug into the issues with both single-page apps and multi-page apps (or, more accurately, websites), and coined a term for a new “somewhere in the middle” approach: transitional apps.
You can watch the whole thing on YouTube now. It’s well worth 20 minutes of your time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Go Make Things</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Better Collaboration With Pull Requests]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352569</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/better-collaboration-with-pull-requests/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T14:29:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article is part of our “Advanced Git” series. Be sure to follow us on Twitter or sign up for our newsletter to hear about the next articles!
In this third installment of our “Advanced Git” series, we’ll look at …
The post Better Collaboration With Pull Requests appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tobias Günther</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[484: Cloudflare, Lying to the Browser, Cloudinary Issues, Vue 2 to Vue 3, and Font Icons]]></title>
        <id>https://shoptalkshow.com/?p=5196</id>
        <link href="https://shoptalkshow.com/484/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T13:45:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're talking about Cloudflare product updates, whether you should lie to the browser about image size, Chris is having Cloudinary issues, Dave's answering questions about upgrading from Vue 2 to Vue 3, a question about Font Awesome icons, and what's the deal with Webhint?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ShopTalk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hasty Treat - Neat Things in CSS Color - Current and Coming!]]></title>
        <id>dccce2d3-f3a8-4f5a-bafb-56ead60eaa41</id>
        <link href="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/syntax/Syntax395.mp3"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this Hasty Treat, Scott and Wes talk about all things color in CSS, both current and coming soon!
 Sentry - Sponsor
 If you want to know what’s happening with your code, track errors and monitor performance with Sentry. Sentry’s Application Monitoring platform helps developers see performance issues, fix errors faster, and optimize their code health. Cut your time on error resolution from hours to minutes. It works with any language and integrates with dozens of other services. Syntax listeners new to Sentry can get two months for free by visiting Sentry.io and using the coupon code TASTYTREAT during sign up.
  Sanity - Sponsor
  Sanity.io is a real-time headless CMS with a fully customizable Content Studio built in React. Get a Sanity powered site up and running in minutes at sanity.io…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Syntax - Tasty Web Development Treats</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[R to @adamwathan: (Thanks @SimonMinton for sharing! 🙌)]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1447545529307652100#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1447545529307652100#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T12:52:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[(Thanks @SimonMinton for sharing! 🙌)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The new @italic website is built with Tailwind CSS 😍

Another beautiful example of a Tailwind site where you'd never know it without peeking into the source 👀

https://italic.com/]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1447545526451376128#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1447545526451376128#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T12:52:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new @italic website is built with Tailwind CSS 😍

Another beautiful example of a Tailwind site where you'd never know it without peeking into the source 👀

italic.com/]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Autofill Dark Pattern]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/autofill-dark-pattern/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/autofill-dark-pattern/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A “dark pattern” is a deceptive UX pattern that tricks users into doing things they may not really want to do. In this article, Alvaro Montoro does a little experiment to find out how much privacy is taken away from users across three different browsers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Alvaro Montoro)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Storyblok is amazing! 💖]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1447497317943291906#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1447497317943291906#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T09:40:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Storyblok is amazing! 💖
nitter.net/storyblok/status/1447476884883791872#m]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@tiptap_editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Been really enjoying “No Rules Rules” — I think you will like it if you are trying to build a team of really talented people doing very creative work with a high degree of autonomy:

https://www.norulesrules.com]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1447334877171494912#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1447334877171494912#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-10T22:54:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Been really enjoying “No Rules Rules” — I think you will like it if you are trying to build a team of really talented people doing very creative work with a high degree of autonomy:

norulesrules.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Rails 6 with Tailwind 2 JIT and Esbuild Without Webpacker]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28819023</id>
        <link href="https://digitmagz.com/using-rails-6-with-tailwind-2-jit-and-esbuild-without-webpacker-b0d5cc13469a"/>
        <updated>2021-10-10T15:13:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://digitmagz.com/using-rails-6-with-tailwind-2-jit-and-esbuild-without-webpacker-b0d5cc13469a
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28819023
Points: 2
# Comments: 0]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nauman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Damn I just realized Hoover from Silicon Valley is Krazee Eyez Killa.]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1446980693033111553#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1446980693033111553#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-09T23:27:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Damn I just realized Hoover from Silicon Valley is Krazee Eyez Killa.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mobile UI components made with Tailwind CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28814248</id>
        <link href="https://tailwind-mobile.com/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-09T23:22:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://tailwind-mobile.com/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28814248
Points: 19
# Comments: 3]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>throwaway888abc</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RT by @adamwathan: Experimenting with implementing our JIT algorithms in Rust to see how the performance would change 🤔 would be hard to do and support a JS-based plugin ecosystem but curious anyways... let's take a quick look!]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/malfaitrobin/status/1446905317825069063#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/malfaitrobin/status/1446905317825069063#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-09T18:28:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Experimenting with implementing our JIT algorithms in Rust to see how the performance would change 🤔 would be hard to do and support a JS-based plugin ecosystem but curious anyways... let's take a quick look!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@malfaitrobin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Composable CSS Animation In Vue With AnimXYZ]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/composable-css-animation-vue-animxyz/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/composable-css-animation-vue-animxyz/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most animation libraries like GSAP and Framer Motion are built purely with JavaScript or TypeScript, unlike AnimXYZ, which is labelled “the first composable CSS animation toolkit”, built mainly with SCSS While a simple library, it can be used to achieve a lot of awesome animation on the web in a short amount of time and little code.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ejiro Asiuwhu)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Case for ‘Developer Experience’]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353429</id>
        <link href="https://future.a16z.com/the-case-for-developer-experience/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T20:23:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A good essay from Jean Yang. 
What I mean by developer experience is the sum total of how developers interface with their tools, end-to-end, day-in and day-out. Sure, there’s more focus than ever on how developers use and adopt tools, and 
…
The post The Case for ‘Developer Experience’ appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jekyll doesn’t do components? Liar!]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353374</id>
        <link href="https://katiekodes.com/jekyll-components-wysiwyg/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T17:14:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I like the pushback from Katie Kodes here. I’ve said in the past that I don’t think server-side languages haven’t quite nailed “building in components” as well as JavaScript has, but hey, this is a good point:
1. Any basic 
…
The post Jekyll doesn’t do components? Liar! appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lots to see in Firefox 93!]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47407</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/10/lots-to-see-in-firefox-93/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T16:45:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 93 comes with lots of lovely updates including AVIF image format support, filling of XFA-based forms in its PDF viewer and protection against insecure downloads by blocking downloads relying on insecure connections.
The post Lots to see in Firefox 93! appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ruth John</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a Tennis Trivia App With Next.js and Netlify]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353066</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/building-a-tennis-trivia-app-with-next-js-and-netlify/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T14:30:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we will be learning how to build a tennis trivia app using Next.js and Netlify. This technology stack has become my go-to on many projects. It allows for rapid development and easy deployment.
Without further ado let’s jump in!…
The post Building a Tennis Trivia App With Next.js and Netlify appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brenley Dueck</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comparing Google Analytics and Plausible Numbers]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353062</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/comparing-google-analytics-and-plausible-numbers/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T14:30:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I saw this blog post the other day: 58% of Hacker News, Reddit and tech-savvy audiences block Google Analytics. That’s an enticing title to me. I’ve had Google Analytics on this site literally from the day I launched it. …
The post Comparing Google Analytics and Plausible Numbers appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Service worker strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://gomakethings.com/service-worker-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://gomakethings.com/service-worker-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just launched a brand new pocket guide on Service Workers. Today, I wanted to take a look at the different types of strategies you can use with service workers.
Let’s dig in!
What is a service worker? A service worker is a special type of JavaScript file that acts like middleware for your site.
Any request that comes from the site and any response it gets back first goes through the service worker file.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Go Make Things</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CEO doesn't care about your CSS strategy, as long as you use Tailwind]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28799487</id>
        <link href="https://ideas.krishnan.ca/your-ceo-doesnt-care-about-your-css-strategy-as-long-as-you-use-tailwind"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T14:12:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://ideas.krishnan.ca/your-ceo-doesnt-care-about-your-css-strategy-as-long-as-you-use-tailwind
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28799487
Points: 8
# Comments: 17]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ajaynomics</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[R to @adamwathan: For what it's worth here's our starting point — literally looks like an episode of hoarders. And yeah that fold up mattress is where I sleep when the baby isn't sleeping well and I need enough rest to function and take care of the other kid the next day 😅]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1446472664349085703#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1446472664349085703#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T13:48:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For what it's worth here's our starting point — literally looks like an episode of hoarders. And yeah that fold up mattress is where I sleep when the baby isn't sleeping well and I need enough rest to function and take care of the other kid the next day 😅]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Static-First MadLib Generator With Portable Text And Netlify On-Demand Builder Functions]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/static-first-madlib-generator-portable-text-netlify-builder-functions/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/static-first-madlib-generator-portable-text-netlify-builder-functions/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be building an interactive fiction experience in which a user can insert words that match parts of speech given by the content creator. Let’s go!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Bryan Robinson)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[That PR takes input/paste rules to the next level. ✨

Feedback appreciated! We’ll release it later today.

https://github.com/ueberdosis/tiptap/pull/1997]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1446384474607005699#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1446384474607005699#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T07:58:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[That PR takes input/paste rules to the next level. ✨

Feedback appreciated! We’ll release it later today.

github.com/ueberdosis/tiptap…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@tiptap_editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RenderingNG deep-dive: LayoutNG]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/layoutng/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/layoutng/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post is a part of a series on the Chromium rendering engine. Check out the rest of the series to learn more about RenderingNG, the architecture, key data structures, and VideoNG.
I'm Ian Kilpatrick,
an engineering lead on the Blink layout team, along with Koji Ishii.
Before working on the Blink team,
I was a front-end engineer (before Google had the role of "front-end engineer"),
building features within Google Docs, Drive, and Gmail.
After around five years in that role I took a large gamble switching to the Blink team,
effectively learning C++ on the job,
and attempting to ramp up on the massively complex Blink codebase.
Even today, I only understand a relatively small portion of it.
I'm grateful for the time given to me during this period.
I was comforted by the fact a lot of "reco…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing Your Own Code Rules]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353112</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/writing-your-own-code-rules/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T23:35:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There comes a time on a project when it’s worth investing in tooling to protect the codebase. I’m not sure how to articulate when, but it’s somewhere after the project has proven to be something long-term and rough edges …
The post Writing Your Own Code Rules appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Developer Decisions For Building Flexible Components]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353386</id>
        <link href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/developer-decisions-building-flexible-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T21:33:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blog posts that get into the whole “how to think like a front-end developer” vibe are my favorite. Michelle Barker nails that in this post, and does it without sharing a line of code!
We simply can no longer 
…
The post Developer Decisions For Building Flexible Components appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vibe Check  №9]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/10/vibe-check-9/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/10/vibe-check-9/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T21:13:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Out on the lake on our neighbor's boat.

September was a good month, a month of rebirth. New projects, rebooting stalled projects, pool closing, kids in school; a rhythm. Walks, boats, ebooks, I even bought a new iPad Mini to support my YouTube and RSS habits. Today my daughter turns six and I’m particularly sensitive to the passage of time. Lots of sunshine, lots of roses, but this month did bring with it some bad news.
Some highlights…

The big news is that Shop Talk started a YouTube series. It’s thrice weekly’ish, 10~20 minute videos over on the CSS Tricks YouTube channel. I wrote a bit about it, but Chris and I are having a good time making videos. We’re up to 12 videos so far. That’s a helluva cadence so there’ll be some breaks, but so far feels pretty sustainable.
I attended Nuxt Na…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm gonna redo my home office and need some inspiration — share some beautiful setups! Stuff that shows off some books, maybe musical gear — bonus points if it includes a nice way to get my Rocket League on without it being a "battlestation" 😅]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1446216140800266247#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1446216140800266247#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T20:49:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm gonna redo my home office and need some inspiration — share some beautiful setups! Stuff that shows off some books, maybe musical gear — bonus points if it includes a nice way to get my Rocket League on without it being a "battlestation" 😅]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The more the merrier 😄]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1446155546617331712#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1446155546617331712#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T16:48:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The more the merrier 😄
nitter.net/mattrothenberg/status/1446150836829270016#m]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go in 100 Seconds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=446E-r0rXHI</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=446E-r0rXHI"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T15:49:35.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Fireship</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Implementing form filling and accessibility in the Firefox PDF viewer]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47372</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/10/implementing-form-filling-and-accessibility-in-the-firefox-pdf-viewer/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T15:13:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year, during lockdown, many discovered the importance of PDF forms when having to deal remotely with administrations and large organizations like banks. Firefox supported displaying PDF forms, but it didn’t support filling them: users had to print them, fill them by hand, and scan them back to digital form. We decided it was time to reinvest in the PDF viewer (PDF.js) and support filling PDF forms within Firefox to make our users' lives easier.
The post Implementing form filling and accessibility in the Firefox PDF viewer appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>bdahl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS in TypeScript with vanilla-extract]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353024</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/css-in-typescript-with-vanilla-extract/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T14:36:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[vanilla-extract is a new framework-agnostic CSS-in-TypeScript library. It’s a lightweight, robust, and intuitive way to write your styles. vanilla-extract isn’t a prescriptive CSS framework, but a flexible piece of developer tooling. CSS tooling has been a relatively stable space over …
The post CSS in TypeScript with vanilla-extract appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hugh Haworth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to delete an item from an array with vanilla JavaScript]]></title>
        <id>https://gomakethings.com/how-to-delete-an-item-from-an-array-with-vanilla-javascript/</id>
        <link href="https://gomakethings.com/how-to-delete-an-item-from-an-array-with-vanilla-javascript/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s say you have an array of wizards, like this.
let wizards = ['Gandalf', 'Radagast', 'Merlin'];  You want to remove the second item, Radagast, from the array. How would you do it?
Let’s dig in!
Using the Array.splice() method The Array.splice() method accepts three arguments: start, delete, and items.
The first, start, is the index of the item you want to modify in the array. It’s the only required argument.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Go Make Things</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using #nextjs? 

GitHub user @‌alb got you covered with the new tiptap installation guide. ⚡️

https://tiptap.dev/installation/nextjs]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1446085632195977218#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1446085632195977218#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T12:10:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using #nextjs? 

GitHub user @‌alb got you covered with the new tiptap installation guide. ⚡️

tiptap.dev/installation/next…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@tiptap_editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Freebie: COVID-19 Icon Set (56 Icons, AI, EPS, SVG, PNG)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/freebie-coronavirus-icon-set/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/freebie-coronavirus-icon-set/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every once in a while, we publish [freebies](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/category/freebies/) related to different occasions and themes. We hope that with this icon set, every designer will be able to find their own use case and contribute to saving lives. Free for personal and commercial use.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Anton Tyschenko)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RT by @adamwathan: I'm nearing completion on my months-long project of rewriting my company's frontend in TypeScript and @tailwindcss. Still, every time I re-implement a component, I think, "Wow, that was way easier this time." Tailwind rocks.🤘🏻]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/mannieschumpert/status/1445868384869134336#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/mannieschumpert/status/1445868384869134336#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T21:47:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm nearing completion on my months-long project of rewriting my company's frontend in TypeScript and @tailwindcss. Still, every time I re-implement a component, I think, "Wow, that was way easier this time." Tailwind rocks.🤘🏻]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@mannieschumpert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RT by @tailwindcss: I'm nearing completion on my months-long project of rewriting my company's frontend in TypeScript and @tailwindcss. Still, every time I re-implement a component, I think, "Wow, that was way easier this time." Tailwind rocks.🤘🏻]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/mannieschumpert/status/1445868384869134336#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/mannieschumpert/status/1445868384869134336#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T21:47:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm nearing completion on my months-long project of rewriting my company's frontend in TypeScript and @tailwindcss. Still, every time I re-implement a component, I think, "Wow, that was way easier this time." Tailwind rocks.🤘🏻]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@mannieschumpert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thanks for sponsoring our open source work! 💖@storyblok]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1445827267859390465#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1445827267859390465#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T19:04:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thanks for sponsoring our open source work! 💖@storyblok]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@tiptap_editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RT by @adamwathan: New home page, who dis? https://savvycal.com/home]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/derrickreimer/status/1445766825657049100#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/derrickreimer/status/1445766825657049100#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T15:04:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New home page, who dis? savvycal.com/home]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@derrickreimer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Control your data for good with Rally]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47420</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/10/control-your-data-for-good-with-rally/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T14:55:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a world where data and AI are reshaping society, people currently have no tangible way to put their data to work for the causes they believe in. To address this, we built the Rally platform, a first-of-its-kind tool that enables you to contribute your data to specific studies and exercise consent at a granular level. Mozilla Rally puts you in control of your data while building a better Internet and a better society. 
The post Control your data for good with Rally appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melissa Thermidor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A practical example of flat file storage]]></title>
        <id>https://gomakethings.com/a-practical-example-of-flat-file-storage/</id>
        <link href="https://gomakethings.com/a-practical-example-of-flat-file-storage/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In yesterday’s article on low upkeep software, I mentioned my love of flat file storage.
 One of the more interesting approaches Jeff uses, and one I’ve done myself for some personal projects, is to store data as flat files.
 One of my students asked me what exactly that means, so today, I wanted to explain a bit more and share a practical example.
Let’s dig in!
What is flat file storage?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Go Make Things</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Potluck — Corn Shucking × Self-Hosting Images × WordPress × Getting Scammed × Portfolios]]></title>
        <id>c9204b4d-7144-4589-bff5-2fd2276fc119</id>
        <link href="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/syntax/Syntax394.mp3"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s another Potluck! In this episode, Scott and Wes answer your questions about corn shucking, self-hosting images, WordPress, getting scammed, portfolios, more!
 Linode - Sponsor
  Whether you’re working on a personal project or managing enterprise infrastructure, you deserve simple, affordable, and accessible cloud computing solutions that allow you to take your project to the next level. Simplify your cloud infrastructure with Linode’s Linux virtual machines and develop, deploy, and scale your modern applications faster and easier. Get started on Linode today with a $100 in free credit for listeners of Syntax. You can find all the details at linode.com/syntax. Linode has 11 global data centers and provides 24/7/365 human support with no tiers or hand-offs regardless of your plan size. …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Syntax - Tasty Web Development Treats</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Commented on my experience with "Shape Up" on HN this morning:

https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28770598]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1445704944523223040#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1445704944523223040#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T10:58:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Commented on my experience with "Shape Up" on HN this morning:

news.ycombinator.com/item?id…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[R to @adamwathan: And yes built-in dark mode support finally too, settle down.]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1445700423080243208#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1445700423080243208#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T10:40:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And yes built-in dark mode support finally too, settle down.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working on fine-grained HTML-based customization for the typography plugin this morning, so you can make your blogs look as beautiful as this 🙈]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1445699794345680898#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1445699794345680898#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T10:37:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Working on fine-grained HTML-based customization for the typography plugin this morning, so you can make your blogs look as beautiful as this 🙈]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To CSS Debugging]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/guide-debugging-css/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/guide-debugging-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging in CSS means figuring out what might be the problem when you have unexpected layout results. We’ll look at a few categories bugs often fit into, see how we can evaluate the situation, and explore techniques that help prevent these bugs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RT by @adamwathan: Cleaning up the @tailwindlabs YouTube channel today, adding Tailwind Play examples to most videos, and updating thumbnails where needed.

Made me realise I created a decent amount of content over time.. 66 videos to be precise 🙌

Here's to many more in the future! 🍻]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/simonswiss/status/1445614543837687808#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/simonswiss/status/1445614543837687808#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T04:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cleaning up the @tailwindlabs YouTube channel today, adding Tailwind Play examples to most videos, and updating thumbnails where needed.

Made me realise I created a decent amount of content over time.. 66 videos to be precise 🙌

Here's to many more in the future! 🍻]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@simonswiss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It’s super trendy to roll your eyes at all idolization of Steve Jobs but the truth is the dude is literally underrated ❤️]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1445526470558826503#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1445526470558826503#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T23:09:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s super trendy to roll your eyes at all idolization of Steve Jobs but the truth is the dude is literally underrated ❤️
nitter.net/Austen/status/1445524262526197760#m]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[📊 Curious, how do you feel about pair programming?]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1445522412020199435#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1445522412020199435#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T22:52:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[📊 Curious, how do you feel about pair programming?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tab Unloading in Firefox 93]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47413</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/10/tab-unloading-in-firefox-93/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T16:52:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starting with Firefox 93, Firefox will monitor available system memory and, should it ever become so critically low that a crash is imminent, Firefox will respond by unloading memory-heavy but not actively used tabs. This feature is currently enabled on Windows and will be deployed later for macOS and Linux as well.
The post Tab Unloading in Firefox 93 appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haik Aftandilian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Low upkeep software]]></title>
        <id>https://gomakethings.com/low-upkeep-software/</id>
        <link href="https://gomakethings.com/low-upkeep-software/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday, I had a chat with Drew McLellan for the Smashing Podcast (the episode won’t come out for a few weeks).
One of the big focuses of our chat was around the illusion of a better developer experience that large JavaScript libraries and modern build processes provide.
They absolutely make some things faster and easier. But they also introduce a delicate house of cards that needs to be constantly maintained.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Go Make Things</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Local Testing A Serverless API (API Gateway And Lambda)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/local-testing-serverless-api-gateway-lambda/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/local-testing-serverless-api-gateway-lambda/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever struggled with testing cloud services locally? Specifically, have you ever struggled with locally testing an API that uses API Gateway and Lambda, with the Serverless framework, on AWS? In this article, Tom Hudson shares a quick overview of how easy it is to quickly set up your project to test locally before deploying to AWS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tom Hudson)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[🙈 Ever wanted to make a small change to one of your old sites and found yourself thinking "ugh I wish I could just use Tailwind for this part"?

Well you can! Learn how to do it without any drawbacks in this new video from @simonswiss 😎

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oG6XPy1t1KA]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/tailwindcss/status/1445080745484107785#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/tailwindcss/status/1445080745484107785#m"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T17:37:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[🙈 Ever wanted to make a small change to one of your old sites and found yourself thinking "ugh I wish I could just use Tailwind for this part"?

Well you can! Learn how to do it without any drawbacks in this new video from @simonswiss 😎

piped.kavin.rocks/watch?v=oG6XPy1t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@tailwindcss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[React Native vs Flutter - I built the same chat app with both]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X8ipUgXH6jw</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X8ipUgXH6jw"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T14:58:18.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Fireship</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[483: Q&A on XState, Getting Comfortable with JavaScript, Managing WordPress Sites, and Background Images in CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://shoptalkshow.com/?p=5173</id>
        <link href="https://shoptalkshow.com/483/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T13:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Chris says, we're back to the meat 'n potatoes of ShopTalk with a Q&A episode including: XState thoughts, getting comfortable with JavaScript, tips on managing several WordPress sites, the best method to schedule high latency tasks with Node.js, a strategy for background images in CSS, and dealing with landing pages and subpages.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ShopTalk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hasty Treat - Spicy Takeout - PHP Is Good and We’re Just Re-Creating It]]></title>
        <id>1837f8a6-fcaa-4cef-b0c8-d3dfd80a2506</id>
        <link href="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/syntax/Syntax393.mp3"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this Hasty Treat, Scott and Wes talk about how much modern web development has taken from PHP!
 Freshbooks - Sponsor
  Get a 30 day free trial of Freshbooks at freshbooks.com/syntax and put SYNTAX in the “How did you hear about us?” section.
  LogRocket - Sponsor
  LogRocket lets you replay what users do on your site, helping you reproduce bugs and fix issues faster. It’s an exception tracker, a session re-player and a performance monitor. Get 14 days free at logrocket.com/syntax.
  Show Notes
  03:56 - Why much of modern web development is just recreating PHP
  
 Everyone loves to hate on PHP, but modern Web dev takes a lot from PHP
  
 05:44 - Mixing templating and logic
  
 We do this with JSX
  
 07:39 - Each request has its own scope
  08:57 - Massive standard lib
  
 Format a date? No sweat!
  Image resizing? Sure!
  Audio bindings? Sure!
  
 10:16 - URL-based routing
  
 Next.js pages
  Serverless functions
  
 11:13 - Server-rendered
  
 Hotwire
  
 11:38 - $_GET, $_POST, are just available
  
 Next.js hooks
  
 12:29 - Variable interpolation
  12:59 - All-in-one frameworks
  
 Laravel did it
  CakePHP
  CodeIgnighter
  
 13:32 - Direct DB access
  
 SQL statements
  
 14:37 - Why do people hate PHP?
  
 WordPress
  Inconsistent API
  Their first code was PHP and they sucked
  PHP has come a long way
  It used to not be safe
  Blocking by default - no async/await
  
 17:48 - Why is JS still better?
  
 Shared code between frontend and backend
  Single language
  Huge ecosystem (could be a con)
  
 Links
  
  Syntax 267: Hasty Treat - Turbolinks + Server Generated HTML + JS Sprinkles
  https://vuejs.org/
  https://www.hey.com/
  
 Tweet us your tasty treats!
  
 Scott’s Instagram
  LevelUpTutorials Instagram
  Wes’ Instagram
  Wes’ Twitter
  Wes’ Facebook
  Scott’s Twitter
  Make sure to include @SyntaxFM in your tweets]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Syntax - Tasty Web Development Treats</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build An Expandable Accessible Gallery]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/build-expandable-accessible-gallery/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/build-expandable-accessible-gallery/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be looking at how to set up a gallery that is expandable as well as accessible with a few tips and tricks along the way. Let’s get started!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Silvestar Bistrović)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Platform News #41]]></title>
        <id>https://www.patreon.com/posts/56962512</id>
        <link href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/56962512"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T00:56:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read on Patreon →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Web Platform News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Chromium Chronicle #25: Thread Safety Annotations]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/chromium-chronicle-25/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/chromium-chronicle-25/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 25: by Victor Costan in SFO (October, 2021)
Previous episodes
In C++, ruling out the possibility of data races comes down to a small thread-safety correctness proof for every data member access.
These proofs add up to a lot of mental toil, especially when reviewing or refactoring code.
Clang's static analysis framework takes over the toil of thread-safety proofs.
# Add GUARDED_BY_CONTEXT() to data members in thread-unsafe classes
Most Chrome classes are thread-unsafe, and should be used on a single sequence.
Add annotations to all data members that are not thread-safe.
Unnecessary annotations are safe, but missing annotations are a risk of data races.
#include "base/sequence_checker.h"  // for SEQUENCE_CHECKER()
#include "base/thread_annotations.h"  // for GUARDED_BY_CONTEXT()
clas…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tailwind Mobile – Pixel perfect mobile UI components built with Tailwind CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28723888</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/tailwind-mobile/tailwind-mobile"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T22:05:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://github.com/tailwind-mobile/tailwind-mobile
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28723888
Points: 4
# Comments: 0]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>chuckrincon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MDN Web Docs at Write the Docs Prague 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://hacks.mozilla.org/?p=47391</id>
        <link href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2021/10/mdn-web-docs-at-write-the-docs-prague-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T12:46:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The MDN Web Docs team is pleased to sponsor Write the Docs Prague 2021, which is being held remotely this year. We’re excited to join hundreds of documentarians to learn more about collaborating with writers, developers, and readers to make better documentation. We plan to take part in all that the conference has to offer, including the Writing Day, Job Fair, and the virtual hallway track.
The post MDN Web Docs at Write the Docs Prague 2021 appeared first on Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Beck</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's new in Svelte: October 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://svelte.dev/blog/whats-new-in-svelte-october-2021</id>
        <link href="https://svelte.dev/blog/whats-new-in-svelte-october-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A whole year of "What's new in Svelte"]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Svelte blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Search Functionality In Your Nuxt App Using Algolia InstantSearch]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/search-functionality-nuxt-app-algolia-instantsearch/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/search-functionality-nuxt-app-algolia-instantsearch/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many websites have some sort of search feature because it helps users navigate through their content easily. Implementing it the right way can be tricky and might not give a good user experience. In this tutorial, we will be integrating Algolia, a popular and powerful search service for the best experience on our Nuxt site.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miracle Onyenma)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RT by @tailwindcss: Long shot but do I know the person who owns http://tailwindcss.dev?]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1443641817346498562#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1443641817346498562#m"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T18:20:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Long shot but do I know the person who owns tailwindcss.dev?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Notes for Safari Technology Preview 133]]></title>
        <id>https://webkit.org/blog/11975/release-notes-for-safari-technology-preview-133/</id>
        <link href="https://webkit.org/blog/11975/release-notes-for-safari-technology-preview-133/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T17:07:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Safari Technology Preview Release 133 is now available for download for macOS Big Sur and betas of macOS Monterey.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>WebKit</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Time Of Transition (October 2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-october-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-october-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Get your desktop ready for fall and the upcoming Halloween season with a fresh batch of desktop wallpapers. Created with love by designers and artists from across the globe, they come in versions with and without a calendar for October 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RT by @tiptap_editor: Seems like @tiptap_editor v2 is finally surpassing the monthly downloads of v1 😅]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/_philippkuehn/status/1443485698900828160#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/_philippkuehn/status/1443485698900828160#m"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T07:59:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Seems like @tiptap_editor v2 is finally surpassing the monthly downloads of v1 😅]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@_philippkuehn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Public Working Draft: Media Source Extensions™]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9265</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9265"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T07:12:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Media Working Group has published a First Public Working Draft of Media Source Extensions™. This specification extends HTMLMediaElement [HTML] to allow JavaScript to generate media streams for playback. Allowing JavaScript to generate streams facilitates a variety of use cases like adaptive streaming and time shifting live streams.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call for Review: Payment Request API and Payment Method Identifiers are W3C Proposed Recommendations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9269</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9269"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T07:10:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Web Payments Working Group has just published Proposed Recommendations of Payment Request API and Payment Method Identifiers. Payment Request standardizes an API to allow merchants (i.e., web sites selling physical or digital goods) to utilize one or more payment methods with minimal integration. Browsers facilitate the payment flow between merchant and user. Payment Method […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call for Review: ARIA in HTML is a W3C Proposed Recommendation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9272</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9272"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T07:09:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Web Applications Working Group has just published a Proposed Recommendation of ARIA in HTML. This specification defines the authoring rules (author conformance requirements) for the use of Accessible Rich Internet Applications (WAI-ARIA) 1.1 and Digital Publishing WAI-ARIA Module 1.0 attributes on [HTML] elements. This specification’s primary objective is to define requirements for use with conformance checking tools used […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress in the Privacy Sandbox (September 2021)]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/progress-in-the-privacy-sandbox-2021-09/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/progress-in-the-privacy-sandbox-2021-09/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the September edition of "Progress in the Privacy
Sandbox" tracking the milestones on the
path to phasing out third-party cookies in Chrome and working towards a more
private web. Each month we'll share an overview of the updates to the Privacy
Sandbox timeline along with news from
across the project.
Prevent covert tracking

User-agent reduction timeline published, changes start from Chrome 101
(stable in Q2 2022) and end with Chrome 113 (stable in Q2 2023)
User-agent reduction early opt-in origin trial registration opened
Strengthen cross-site privacy
boundaries

Initial origin trial for First-Party Sets concluded
DevTools cookie functionality improved
Show relevant content and ads

Extending the overall Discussion period to Q4 2021 and starting the Testing
period in Q1 2022
H…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RT by @tailwindcss: Congratulations to @tailwindcss on hitting 1 million weekly downloads 🎉🎉]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/github/status/1443335427327336450#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/github/status/1443335427327336450#m"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T22:02:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Congratulations to @tailwindcss on hitting 1 million weekly downloads 🎉🎉
nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1443294163160682503#m]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@github</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RT by @tailwindcss: Just noticed that Tailwind CSS has crossed 1M weekly downloads! 🤯

What the hell man, this was just supposed to be a couple of stupid stylesheets I copied around between failed SaaS ideas for years on end 😅]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1443294163160682503#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1443294163160682503#m"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T19:18:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just noticed that Tailwind CSS has crossed 1M weekly downloads! 🤯

What the hell man, this was just supposed to be a couple of stupid stylesheets I copied around between failed SaaS ideas for years on end 😅]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Show HN: Flowrift – Tailwind CSS UI Blocks]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28698302</id>
        <link href="https://flowrift.com"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T19:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://flowrift.com
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28698302
Points: 7
# Comments: 9]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>sergejcodes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changelog Frontend Feud]]></title>
        <id>f8c38a43-70e3-4845-8337-7248c69a0247</id>
        <link href="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/syntax/Syntax392.mp3"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Syntax, Scott and Wes do a crossover episode with Changelog’s JS Party! Your favorite web dev podcasts join forces for a super collab that’ll knock you frontend off! Amelia joins Chris Coyier and Dave Rupert from ShopTalk Show, while Divya teams up with Wes Bos and Scott Tolinski from Syntax. Let the FEUDing begin!
 .TECH Domains - Sponsor
  .TECH is taking the tech industry by storm. A domain that shows the world what you are all about! If you’re looking for a domain name for your startup, portfolio, or your own project like we did with uses.tech, check out .tech Domains. Syntax listeners can snap their .TECH Domains at 80% off on five-year registration by visiting go.tech/syntaxistech and using the coupon code “syntax5”.
  LogRocket - Sponsor
  LogRocket lets you repla…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Syntax - Tasty Web Development Treats</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Modern Image Formats: AVIF And WebP]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/modern-image-formats-avif-webp/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/modern-image-formats-avif-webp/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T08:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll highlight how modern image formats (AVIF or WebP) can improve compression by up to 50% and deliver better quality per-byte while still looking visually appealing. We’ll compare what’s possible at high-quality, low-quality and file-size targets.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Addy Osmani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Slick 👌]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1442953045810221056#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1442953045810221056#m"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T20:43:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Slick 👌
nitter.net/samjshore/status/1442942711900688386#m]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@tiptap_editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use Tailwind CSS to Build HTML Email Templates]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28687075</id>
        <link href="https://dev.to/ehlo_250/set-of-free-mit-transactional-email-templates-built-using-tailwind-css-4n12"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T20:26:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://dev.to/ehlo_250/set-of-free-mit-transactional-email-templates-built-using-tailwind-css-4n12
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28687075
Points: 4
# Comments: 0]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>albertgoeswoof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[React Native in 100 Seconds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gvkqT_Uoahw</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gvkqT_Uoahw"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T15:56:21.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Fireship</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You know those cool thumbnails we use for all of our YouTube videos?

Learn how to make it from scratch with Tailwind CSS in, well, a new YouTube video! 🥳

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qyBexrnBz_I]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/tailwindcss/status/1442876004700016640#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/tailwindcss/status/1442876004700016640#m"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T15:37:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You know those cool thumbnails we use for all of our YouTube videos?

Learn how to make it from scratch with Tailwind CSS in, well, a new YouTube video! 🥳

piped.kavin.rocks/watch?v=qyBexrnB…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@tailwindcss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DOM Review Draft Published 15 June 2020 is a W3C Recommendation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9262</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9262"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T09:48:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As part of working with the WHATWG together on HTML and DOM, W3C selected today to endorse the DOM Review Draft — Published 15 June 2020 as a W3C Recommendation. DOM defines a platform-neutral model for events, aborting activities, and node trees. For more information, see the blog post WHATWG Review Drafts of HTML and […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Accessibility Of Your Markdown]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/improving-accessibility-of-markdown/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/improving-accessibility-of-markdown/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can find Markdown in many places on the Internet. This article covers different aspects of Markdown and how it interacts with other technology.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Eric Bailey)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Public Working Draft: Synchronization Accessibility User Requirements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9260</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9260"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T08:47:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Accessible Platform Architectures Working Group has published a First Public Working Draft of Synchronization Accessibility User Requirements. This document outlines accessibility-related user needs and associated requirements for the synchronization of multimedia. The successful synchronization of multimedia content, especially audio and video, is essential to accessible web-based communication and cooperation. Understandable media is therefore media […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueyuan Jia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new example to show how you can force a title …✨

… and use dynamic placeholders. 💫

https://tiptap.dev/examples/custom-document]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1442768037749395461#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1442768037749395461#m"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T08:28:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new example to show how you can force a title …✨

… and use dynamic placeholders. 💫

tiptap.dev/examples/custom-d…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@tiptap_editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What he says 👇️]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1442589957181296649#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1442589957181296649#m"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T20:40:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What he says 👇️
nitter.net/barakcodes/status/1442584740322816002#m]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@tiptap_editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RT by @tiptap_editor: If you're planning on making a WSYWIG/ Markdown editor. I can easily recommend  @tiptap_editor  hands down.
 💎   It's easy to use
💎  It is less complex
💎  Offers a lot of flexibility]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/barakcodes/status/1442584740322816002#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/barakcodes/status/1442584740322816002#m"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T20:19:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're planning on making a WSYWIG/ Markdown editor. I can easily recommend  @tiptap_editor  hands down.
 💎   It's easy to use
💎  It is less complex
💎  Offers a lot of flexibility]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@barakcodes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Set of TailwindCSS Based Transactional HTML Email Templates]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28672926</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/ohmysmtp/templates"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T16:42:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://github.com/ohmysmtp/templates
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28672926
Points: 14
# Comments: 18]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>albertgoeswoof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solidity in 100 Seconds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kdvVwGrV7ec</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kdvVwGrV7ec"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T15:11:25.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Fireship</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hasty Treat - Desktop Apps + New Tech We Love]]></title>
        <id>992bf148-3315-4457-8f32-141795c8cad8</id>
        <link href="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/syntax/Syntax391.mp3"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this Hasty Treat, Scott and Wes talk about the hottest new tech they love!
 Linode - Sponsor
  Whether you’re working on a personal project or managing enterprise infrastructure, you deserve simple, affordable, and accessible cloud computing solutions that allow you to take your project to the next level. Simplify your cloud infrastructure with Linode’s Linux virtual machines and develop, deploy, and scale your modern applications faster and easier. Get started on Linode today with a $100 in free credit for listeners of Syntax. You can find all the details at linode.com/syntax. Linode has 11 global data centers and provides 24/7/365 human support with no tiers or hand-offs regardless of your plan size. In addition to shared and dedicated compute instances, you can use your $100 in credi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Syntax - Tasty Web Development Treats</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[482: Asset Pipeline Issues, Google ZX, Crazy CSS, and a New CSS Reset]]></title>
        <id>https://shoptalkshow.com/?p=5147</id>
        <link href="https://shoptalkshow.com/482/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T12:48:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join us on YouTube 3x a week for more ShopTalk fun. This episode: How would you build with maximum user growth in mind? Asset pipeline issues, self provisioning runtime, Google ZX, and crazy new CSS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ShopTalk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s Dive Into Cypress For End-to-End Testing]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/cypress-end-to-end-testing/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/cypress-end-to-end-testing/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is end-to-end testing a painful topic for you? In this article, Ramona Schwering explains how to handle end-to-end testing with Cypress and make it make it not so tedious and expensive for yourself, but fun instead.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ramona Schwering)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome Web Store policy updates for Q3 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/policy-update-kwspam-and-circumvention/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/policy-update-kwspam-and-circumvention/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the years we've made a number of product and policy improvements to help ensure a quality
experience for both users and developers. As part of this work, we've updated our best practices,
and identifiednamed undesirable behaviors that create spammy experiences for users. Today, we're
furthering this work by clarifying and updating two policies, to keep the quality of extensions
high, and the experience for developers consistent:
# Keyword Spam Update
Keyword Spam is the practice of including irrelevant or excessive keywords in an extensions
description in an attempt to manipulate its ranking, resulting in a spammy, negative user
experience. We don't allow extensions with misleading, improperly formatted, non-descriptive,
irrelevant, excessive, or inappropriate metadata, including but …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome user device characteristics report]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/device-characteristics/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/device-characteristics/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Developers are constantly wondering about what kind of audience they are
developing for. Are they using high end devices with large RAM? What connection
are they using (for example Wi-Fi, 2G) and so on. The answers to these questions
can affect product development decisions such as choosing the
technologies to render the content. This report provides timeline data to inform
developers on these questions for a list of countries, such as the US, Brazil,
Japan, and others. Three platforms are included when data is available: Android,
Windows, and ChromeOS.
Looking at the data, there might be some interesting things for developers to
think about. For example, in Japan on the Android platform, the majority of
users have five to eight cores, and the prevalence is quite a bit higher than in
the US, and much higher than in next billion user (NBU) countries. Another
example: if you look at RAM on Android, a very low percentage of Brazil devices
have RAM larger than 5 GB, which is much lower than in the US, and also lower
than India. We hope publishing information like this periodically will help
developers have a better understanding of the Chrome user device
characteristics.
This data comes from usage statistics sent to Google from Chrome installations.
In Chrome, users can choose to send usage statistics and crash reports to Google
to help improve Chrome's feature set and stability. Usage statistics and crash
reports are enabled by default for Chrome consumer installs and can be disabled
during installation or in Chrome's settings. Metrics collection is pseudonymous,
and metrics are tagged by an opaque per-install identifier that is not joinable
with other datasets.  If the metrics collection is re-enabled, the unique
identifier will also be reset. We used the data collected to calculate the
various statistics in this
report.
Photo by Halacious on Unsplash]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.2]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T18:45:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: unicode characters in URL caused download error
Fixed: project root npm install error
Added: unit test library
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @CaptNo1]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I changed my mind about Tailwind CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28645995</id>
        <link href="https://www.thomasdhondt.be/blog/i-changed-my-mind-about-tailwind-css"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T18:19:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.thomasdhondt.be/blog/i-changed-my-mind-about-tailwind-css
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28645995
Points: 1
# Comments: 1]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>gymshoes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shop Talk Goes Video]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/09/shop-talk-goes-video/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/09/shop-talk-goes-video/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T17:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[🎉 After nearly ten years of weekly podcasts, Shop Talk has entered into a new realm: Video. Under the umbrella of the CSS-Tricks YouTube channel we’ve started posting daily-ish videos about front-end web development. This is a 🔥 year for CSS, so there’s no shortage of topics or #hotdrama to talk about and demo.
We’re still dialing in the formula, but it’s shaping up to look like 15~20 minute videos delivered thrice weekly. Math-wise, that’s not too different than doing another one hour podcast every week. Video of course is a little more involved, you need to spend a bit more effort planning out tech demos. Keeping our same (overly?) casual feel makes it all sustainable for us. If Chris and I were doing video content full time it might make sense to write and edit a bit more, but both of us have day jobs, are running companies, and contributing code.
One nice by-product of exploring video is that we get a chance to re-explain mouth-coding examples or overly visual concepts that were probably confusing on the audio podcast. As much as I love podcasting, the lack of visual examples for a visual field like Web Design and Development is a limitation. I like that the YouTube series is like supplementary material to ideas covered in the podcast, rather than a replacement.
Okay! That’s it! I hope you enjoy the little foray into video.
Watch on YouTube
And I wouldn’t be a YouTuber if I didn’t say… Be sure to drop a like and subscribe, that really helps us out in the algorithm. And ring that bell for notifications when new videos come out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to OVER Engineer a Website // What is a Tech Stack?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Sxxw3qtb3_g</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Sxxw3qtb3_g"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T14:41:18.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Fireship</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rebuilding A Large E-Commerce Website With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/lessons-learned-ecommerce-nextjs-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/lessons-learned-ecommerce-nextjs-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We made the switch from a more traditional integrated e-commerce platform to a headless platform with Next.js. Here are the most important lessons learned while rebuilding a large e-commerce site with Next.js.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jonne Kats)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Online Workshop: Frustrating Design Patterns And How To Fix Them]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/smashing-workshop-frustrating-design-patterns/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/smashing-workshop-frustrating-design-patterns/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T06:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’ve seen them before. Confusing and frustrating design patterns that seem to be chasing you everywhere you go, from one website to another. It’s time to fix them for good in a [free Smashing online workshop](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/workshops/vitaly-friedman-frustrating-patterns/) next week.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Show HN: Demo of Tailwind CSS, Gulpjs, Alpine.js (Version 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28637327</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/joelparkerhenderson/demo-tailwind-css"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T00:36:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://github.com/joelparkerhenderson/demo-tailwind-css
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28637327
Points: 5
# Comments: 0]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jph</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can someone chime in and share experiences with Matthew? 🙌]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1441079121132593163#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1441079121132593163#m"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T16:36:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Can someone chime in and share experiences with Matthew? 🙌
nitter.net/mattkrick/status/1441071611998658572#m]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@tiptap_editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All things are possible with code, but not everything is beneficial]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/09/all-things-possible-not-everything-beneficial/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/09/all-things-possible-not-everything-beneficial/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T15:49:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In my weird role as hybrid contractor/consultant I get asked, “Is it possible to do {{some_feature}}?” and what goes through my head is a bastardized version of the Apostle Paul saying:
All things are possible (with code), but not everything is beneficial.
The answer to “Can you make {{feature}} with code?” is almost always “Yes.” Given infinite time, infinite budget, infinite lines of code, and infinite opportunities for failure; I’m almost certain we can come up with a working solution for any scenario you can dream up. There’s JavaScript in space, I’m sure we can figure out your idea.
Now does it work for the user? Would it explode the timeline and scope? Does it add an immense amount of complexity and technical debt? Would it tear the social fabric of American democracy in the process?…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simplifying Form Styles With `accent-color`]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/simplifying-form-styles-accent-color/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/simplifying-form-styles-accent-color/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new CSS `accent-color` property makes it quick and easy to roll out our brand colors to certain form inputs by leveraging user agent styles. In this article we’ll take a look at what it does and how to use it alongside `color-scheme` for simple, accessible checkboxes and radio buttons — and imagine how we might use it in the future.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Michelle Barker)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s check if we can load the whole Moby Dick novel into tiptap … 

Yup, works just fine, even with 200,000 words. ⚡️

https://tiptap.dev/examples/book]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1440964403814445059#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/tiptap_editor/status/1440964403814445059#m"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T09:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s check if we can load the whole Moby Dick novel into tiptap … 

Yup, works just fine, even with 200,000 words. ⚡️

tiptap.dev/examples/book]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@tiptap_editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Show HN: A Tool to Rapidly Prototype and Build Webpages Using Tailwind CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28626065</id>
        <link href="https://www.devwares.com/windframe"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T07:07:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.devwares.com/windframe
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28626065
Points: 3
# Comments: 1]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>overwatch02</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Notion Blogging Kanban]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/09/my-notion-blogging-kanban/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/09/my-notion-blogging-kanban/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T00:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Six years ago, I started a good blogging habit of writing down any idea I had as a draft post. This was a good practice because the idea was now out of my head and I wouldn’t stay up at night thinking about it. Over time that grew to about eighty posts in different states of completeness and it became overwhelming. 16,000+ words, terribly organized.
A flat folder full of alphabetically sorted markdown files was not intuitively useful. I had no idea which posts were most recent, which were almost done, and which needed to go away. Lots of those drafts were a zingy title and a vague one-liner of text. Reverse engineering my own ideas when I revisited them later was difficult. It became mentally taxing to manage my own blog.
In a fit of desperation, I took my posts one step away from “the met…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The transition of Chrome extensions to Manifest V3]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/mv2-transition/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/mv2-transition/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this year, for Chrome 88, we announced the availability of a new manifest
version for the
Chrome extension ecosystem. Years in the making, Manifest V3 is more secure, performant, and
privacy-preserving than its predecessor. It is an evolution of the extension platform that takes
into consideration both the changing web landscape and the future of browser extensions.
As we look to the future by continuing to iterate on and improve upon Manifest V3 functionality, we
also want to share details about the plan to phase out Manifest V2 extensions.
There are two key dates for the phase-out:
January 17, 2022: New Manifest V2 extensions will no longer be accepted by the Chrome Web
Store. Developers may still push updates to existing Manifest V2 extensions, but no new Manifest
V2 items may b…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deprecations and removals in Chrome 95]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/deps-rems-95/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/deps-rems-95/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit ChromeStatus.com for lists of current deprecations and previous removals.
Chrome 95 beta was released on September 23, 2021 and is expected to become the
stable version in late October, 2021.
# FTP support removed
Chrome is removing support for FTP
URLs. Use of FTP in the
browser is sufficiently low that it is no longer viable to invest in improving
the existing FTP client. In addition, more capable FTP clients are available on
all affected platforms.
Google Chrome 72 and later removed support for fetching document subresources
over FTP and rendering of top level FTP resources. Currently navigating to FTP
URLs results in showing a directory listing or a download depending on the type
of resource. A bug in Google Chrome 74 and later resulted in dropping support for
accessing FTP URLs …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Your `head` Straight: A New CSS Performance Diagnostics Snippet]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/css-head-tag/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/css-head-tag/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We love little useful tools and techniques to help folks get their work done better and faster. Today, we’d love to shine the spotlights on a little helper that helps spot common performance bottlenecks easily: [ct.css](https://csswizardry.com/ct/).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From React To SvelteKit]]></title>
        <id>4817c5e0-4cac-4ad0-8da6-abe9f55a6abb</id>
        <link href="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/syntax/Syntax390.mp3"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Syntax, Scott talks with Wes about moving Level Up Tutorials from React to SvelteKit — why he did it, how, benefits, things to watch out for, and more!
 Prismic - Sponsor
  Prismic is a Headless CMS that makes it easy to build website pages as a set of components. Break pages into sections of components using React, Vue, or whatever you like. Make corresponding Slices in Prismic. Start building pages dynamically in minutes. Get started at prismic.io/syntax.
  Sentry - Sponsor
 If you want to know what’s happening with your code, track errors and monitor performance with Sentry. Sentry’s Application Monitoring platform helps developers see performance issues, fix errors faster, and optimize their code health. Cut your time on error resolution from hours to minutes. It wor…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Syntax - Tasty Web Development Treats</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[D3.js in 100 Seconds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bp2GF8XcJdY</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bp2GF8XcJdY"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T17:04:07.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Fireship</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[🚀 New screencast day!

Learn how to build a simple headless ecommerce site with Tailwind CSS, Shopify, and Next.js 🛍

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xNMYz74zNHM]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/tailwindcss/status/1440343008348573710#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/tailwindcss/status/1440343008348573710#m"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T15:51:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[🚀 New screencast day!

Learn how to build a simple headless ecommerce site with Tailwind CSS, Shopify, and Next.js 🛍

piped.kavin.rocks/watch?v=xNMYz74z…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@tailwindcss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RT by @tailwindcss: 🔥 Working with gradients that fade to transparent is really annoying in Safari because you have to fade to a transparent version of your starting color to avoid fading through gray.

In Tailwind, just leave off the "to" color and we calculate the proper transparent by default 👍🏻]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1440311263012085760#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/adamwathan/status/1440311263012085760#m"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T13:45:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[🔥 Working with gradients that fade to transparent is really annoying in Safari because you have to fade to a transparent version of your starting color to avoid fading through gray.

In Tailwind, just leave off the "to" color and we calculate the proper transparent by default 👍🏻]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@adamwathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build Your Own Mouseless Development Environment]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/mouseless-development-environment/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/mouseless-development-environment/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building a development environment with the shell as a keystone offers multiple benefits. You can customize everything depending on your own needs, and the biggest of all, you can control your entire development environment with your keyboard.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Matthieu Cneude)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Public Working Draft: WebRTC Encoded Transform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.w3.org/blog/news/?p=9258</id>
        <link href="https://www.w3.org/blog/news/archives/9258"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T11:19:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Web Real-Time Communications Working Group has published a First Public Working Draft of WebRTC Encoded Transform. The goal of this work is to define an API for processing encoded media in WebRTC, for example for voice processing, background removal, dynamic control of codec parameters, etc. This document specifies an API surface for manipulating the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Coralie Mercier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Web Development Tools Are Helping Users Keep Pace With Rapid Change]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/web-development-tools-users-keep-pace-rapid-change/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/web-development-tools-users-keep-pace-rapid-change/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The last 18 months have been a time of unprecedented turbulence. As the people of the world have flooded online, businesses have joined them, using web development tools to adapt in real-time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New in Chrome 94]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/new-in-chrome-94/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/new-in-chrome-94/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's what you need to know:
The default color space for <canvas> elements is
now formally defined  in the spec as SRGB, and you can change it to
Display P3.
WebCodecs is a new, low level way to access built in audio and
video codecs, important for streaming games, video editors, and such.
WebGPU starts its origin trial.
The PWA Summit is coming up October 6-7.
And there's plenty more.
I'm Pete LePage, working, and shooting
from home, let's dive in and see what's new for developers in Chrome 94.
# Default color space for canvas elements
How color is rendered on screen is critical to some users. For photographers,
print illustrators, and many others, the colors on screen need to match what's
printed. Starting in Chrome 94, <canvas> elements are fully color managed
using sRGB. Previously, s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RT by @tailwindcss: I'm going to be doing a presentation at @SoFriedDNN to help convince #DNN developers to use @tailwindcss . Anyone have good examples of really high profile sites using #tailwindcss ? For example, http://meetup.com]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/ajplopez/status/1440047167821938704#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/ajplopez/status/1440047167821938704#m"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T20:16:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm going to be doing a presentation at @SoFriedDNN to help convince #DNN developers to use @tailwindcss . Anyone have good examples of really high profile sites using #tailwindcss ? For example, meetup.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@ajplopez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Content Platforms Explained in 100 Seconds // Build your own with Sanity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c_8cplBi_gE</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c_8cplBi_gE"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T17:54:07.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Fireship</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Platform Weekly #40]]></title>
        <id>https://www.patreon.com/posts/56383553</id>
        <link href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/56383553"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T14:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read on Patreon →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Web Platform News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[481: Frontend Feud: ShopTalk vs Syntax]]></title>
        <id>https://shoptalkshow.com/?p=5127</id>
        <link href="https://shoptalkshow.com/481/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T13:25:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Crossover! Your favorite web dev podcasts join forces for a super collab that’ll knock you frontend off! Amelia joins Chris Coyier and Dave Rupert from ShopTalk Show while Divya teams up with Wes Bos & Scott Tolinski from Syntax. Let the FEUDing begin!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ShopTalk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hasty Treat - Webhooks]]></title>
        <id>da53ef35-ec58-4629-8668-c468fe3ebab7</id>
        <link href="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/syntax/Syntax389.mp3"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this Hasty Treat, Scott and Wes talk about webhooks — one of those concepts that seems a lot scarier than it actually is.
 Linode - Sponsor
  Whether you’re working on a personal project or managing enterprise infrastructure, you deserve simple, affordable, and accessible cloud computing solutions that allow you to take your project to the next level. Simplify your cloud infrastructure with Linode’s Linux virtual machines and develop, deploy, and scale your modern applications faster and easier. Get started on Linode today with a $100 in free credit for listeners of Syntax. You can find all the details at linode.com/syntax. Linode has 11 global data centers and provides 24/7/365 human support with no tiers or hand-offs regardless of your plan size. In addition to shared and dedicated co…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Syntax - Tasty Web Development Treats</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Imposter Domains Re-Publishing Your Website?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/imposter-domains-republishing-website/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/imposter-domains-republishing-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Content scraping is a fact of life on the Internet. When you think of web scraping, you probably do not think about the scrapers turning around and immediately serving your entire, whole page content on another website. But what if your site content is being re-published?  It might be already happening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ken Harker)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's New In DevTools (Chrome 95)]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/new-in-devtools-95/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/new-in-devtools-95/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Interested in helping improve DevTools? Sign up to participate in Google User Research here.
# New CSS length authoring tools
DevTools added an easier yet flexible way to update lengths in CSS!
In the Styles pane, look for any CSS property with length (e.g. height, padding).
Hover over the unit type, and notice the unit type is underlined. Click on it to select a unit type from the dropdown.
          
Hover over the unit value, and your mouse pointer is changed to horizontal cursor. Drag horizontally to increase or decrease the value. To adjust the value by 10, hold the Shift key when dragging.
          
You can still edit the unit value as text — just click on the value and start editing.
          
Chromium issues: 1126178, 1172993
# Hide issues in the Issues tab
You can now hide speci…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Create HTML Emails with TailwindCSS]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28582415</id>
        <link href="https://maizzle.com/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-19T07:31:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://maizzle.com/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28582415
Points: 1
# Comments: 0]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>albertgoeswoof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RT by @tailwindcss: Really happy with how the new Tailwind docs examples are coming along. Trying to use more practical examples to explain the concepts where possible. 

Here's a few I put together to explain overflow scroll utilities 👉]]></title>
        <id>https://nitter.net/steveschoger/status/1438878483388768263#m</id>
        <link href="https://nitter.net/steveschoger/status/1438878483388768263#m"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T14:52:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Really happy with how the new Tailwind docs examples are coming along. Trying to use more practical examples to explain the concepts where possible. 

Here's a few I put together to explain overflow scroll utilities 👉]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>@steveschoger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monetize Open-Source Software With Gatsby Functions And Stripe]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/monetize-open-source-software-gatsby-functions-stripe/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/monetize-open-source-software-gatsby-functions-stripe/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gatsby Functions provide front-end developers a way to write and use server-side code without the hassle of maintaining a server. If making money from open-source is of interest to you and your site isn’t built using Gatsby, this approach may well be the answer you were looking for.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Paul Scanlon)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Show HN: Flowbite – Tailwind CSS Components Library]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28561468</id>
        <link href="https://flowbite.com/docs/getting-started/introduction/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T05:14:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://flowbite.com/docs/getting-started/introduction/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28561468
Points: 77
# Comments: 59]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>zoltanszogyenyi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Notes for Safari Technology Preview 132]]></title>
        <id>https://webkit.org/blog/11971/release-notes-for-safari-technology-preview-132/</id>
        <link href="https://webkit.org/blog/11971/release-notes-for-safari-technology-preview-132/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T21:16:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Safari Technology Preview Release 132 is now available for download for macOS Big Sur and betas of macOS Monterey.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>WebKit</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to "Google It" like a Senior Software Engineer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cEBkvm0-rg0</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cEBkvm0-rg0"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T14:58:44.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Fireship</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Quality Assurance: From User Requirements To Web Risk Management]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/journey-into-web-quality-assurance/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/journey-into-web-quality-assurance/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twenty years ago, Elie Sloïm chose to dedicate his professional life to web quality assurance. He started asking, ”What does quality mean for a web user?” Well, this article explains everything he has learned along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Elie Sloïm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reasons To Build A CRM-Powered Website For Your Business]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/reasons-build-crm-powered-website-business/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/reasons-build-crm-powered-website-business/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Integrating a CRM with your business website has numerous benefits. In this article, Zara Cooper explains what these benefits are and why websites should be integrated with a CRM platform.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Zara Cooper)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.1]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.1</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.1"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T06:39:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: Unexpected nested element in author field crashes the parser
Thank you @ad-m]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Mirror Editing in Edge DevTools for VS Code]]></title>
        <id>https://christianheilmann.com/?p=6959</id>
        <link href="https://christianheilmann.com/2021/09/16/css-mirror-editing-in-edge-devtools-for-vs-code/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T06:16:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Summary: With the release of 1.3.1 of the Edge Tools for VS Code we introduce a better way to get changes you made in the Styles tool back into your source code. We’d love to know what you think of it and what we can do better. There’s a GitHub issue dedicated to feedback. Developer […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uniquely identifying PWAs with the web app manifest id property]]></title>
        <id>https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/pwa-manifest-id/</id>
        <link href="https://developer.chrome.com/en/blog/pwa-manifest-id/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When the user installs your PWA, the browser needs a way to uniquely identify
the PWA. But, until recently, the web app manifest spec didn't explicitly
define a way to uniquely identify a PWA, leaving browsers to decide and
leading to different implementations. In some browsers, the start_url
is used, while in others, the path to the manifest file is used, making it
impossible to update either of those fields.
To solve this issue, there's a new optional id property in the web app
manifest spec, that allows you to explicitly define the identifier used for
your PWA. Adding the id property to the manifest removes the dependency on
the start_url or the location of the manifest, and makes it possible for
them to be updated in the future.
# What does the id property do?
The id property represent…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrome Developers - Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>